=-DOCSTART-	O


While	O
Winona	ACTOR
Ryder	ACTOR
's	O
enjoying	O
another	O
moment	O
in	O
the	O
sun	O
thanks	O
to	O
her	O
stunning	O
turn	O
in	O
"	O
Black	MOVIE
Swan	MOVIE
,"	O
she	O
's	O
also	O
airing	O
some	O
dirty	O
laundry	O
,	O
and	O
not	O
all	O
of	O
it	O
is	O
hers	O
.	O


More	O
Video	O


In	O
the	O
January	O
2011	O
issue	O
of	O
GQ	NEWSPAPER
magazine	O
,	O
Ryder	ACTOR
claims	O
she	O
's	O
known	O
about	O
Mel	ACTOR
Gibson	ACTOR
's	O
not-so-palatable	O
side	O
for	O
years	O
.	O

She	O
shared	O
an	O
anecdote	O
about	O
the	O
actor	O
:	O


"	O
I	O
remember	O
,	O
like	O
,	O
fifteen	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
I	O
was	O
at	O
one	O
of	O
those	O
big	O
Hollywood	CITY
parties	O
.	O
And	O
he	O
was	O
really	O
drunk	O
.	O
I	O
was	O
with	O
my	O
friend	O
,	O
who	O
's	O
gay	O
.	O
He	O
made	O
a	O
really	O
horrible	O
gay	O
joke	O
.	O

And	O
somehow	O
it	O
came	O
up	O
that	O
I	O
was	O
Jewish	O
.	O
He	O
said	O
something	O
about	O
'	O
oven	O
dodgers	O
,'	O
but	O
I	O
didn	O
't	O
get	O
it	O
.	O
I	O
'd	O
never	O
heard	O
that	O
before	O
.	O
It	O
was	O
just	O
this	O
weird	O
,	O
weird	O
moment	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
like	O
,	O
'	O
He	O
's	O
anti-Semitic	O
and	O
he	O
's	O
homophobic	O
.'	O
No	O
one	O
believed	O
me	O
!"	O


Gibson	ACTOR
's	O
publicist	O
did	O
not	O
immediately	O
respond	O
to	O
ABCNews.com	ORGANIZATION
's	O
calls	O
for	O
comment	O
.	O


Ryder	ACTOR
's	O
latest	O
stint	O
in	O
the	O
spotlight	O
comes	O
courtesy	O
of	O
her	O
small	O
but	O
juicy	O
role	O
as	O
an	O
aging	O
former	O
ingénue	O
displaced	O
by	O
Natalie	ACTOR
Portman	ACTOR
's	O
budding	O
ingénue	O
in	O
"	O
Black	MOVIE
Swan	MOVIE
."	O
After	O
growing	O
up	O
on	O
film	O
sets	O
,	O
starring	O
in	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
iconic	O
roles	O
of	O
the	O
80s	O
and	O
90s	O
and	O
seeing	O
her	O
career	O
derailed	O
by	O
a	O
shoplifting	O
scandal	O
,	O
Ryder	ACTOR
is	O
no	O
longer	O
the	O
new	O
kid	O
on	O
the	O
block	O
.	O


"	O
I	O
did	O
relate	O
to	O
Beth	PERSON
on	O
a	O
certain	O
level	O
,"	O
she	O
said	O
in	O
the	O
current	O
issue	O
of	O
Elle	NEWSPAPER
about	O
her	O
character	O
in	O
"	O
Swan	MOVIE
."	O
"	O
Just	O
that	O
thing	O
of	O
,	O
you	O
know	O
,	O
when	O
I	O
'm	O
told	O
I	O
'm	O
not	O
the	O
ingÃ	O
©	O
nue	O
anymore	O
.	O
And	O
now	O
I	O
'm	O
39	O
.	O
I	O
remember	O
when	O
I	O
was	O
younger	O
,	O
I	O
couldn	O
't	O
wait	O
to	O
be	O
older	O
,	O
because	O
I	O
was	O
always	O
the	O
kid	O
on	O
the	O
set	O
,	O
I	O
was	O
always	O
younger	O
than	O
everyone	O
else	O
.	O

And	O
now	O
I	O
'm	O
older	O
than	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
I	O
work	O
with	O
.	O
I	O
've	O
been	O
doing	O
this	O
for	O
25	O
years	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
so	O
strange	O
."	O


"	O
I	O
was	O
watching	O
TV	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
was	O
this	O
oldies-but-goodies	O
film	O
fest	O
,	O
and	O
'	O
Lucas	MOVIE
'	O
came	O
on	O
.	O
I	O
was	O
like	O
,	O
'	O
Oh	O
my	O
God	O
,	O
I	O
'm	O
an	O
oldie	O
!'"	O
Ryder	ACTOR
recounted	O
.	O


Winona	ACTOR
Ryder	ACTOR
with	O
Christian	ACTOR
Slater	ACTOR
in	O
'	O
Heathers	MOVIE
.'	O


Released	O
in	O
1986	O
,	O
"	O
Lucas	MOVIE
"	O
was	O
Ryder	ACTOR
's	O
first	O
film	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
she	O
played	O
opposite	O
Corey	ACTOR
Haim	ACTOR
and	O
Charlie	ACTOR
Sheen	ACTOR
.	O

She	O
followed	O
it	O
with	O
roles	O
as	O
a	O
goth	O
teen	O
in	O
"	O
Bettlejuice	MOVIE
,"	O
a	O
teenage	O
murderess	O
in	O
"	O
Heathers	MOVIE
,"	O
Johnny	ACTOR
Depp	ACTOR
's	O
on	O
(	O
and	O
off	O
)	O
screen	O
girlfriend	O
in	O
"	O
Edward	MOVIE
Scissorhands	MOVIE
,"	O
and	O
a	O
Gen	MISC
Xer	MISC
in	O
"	O
Reality	MOVIE
Bites	MOVIE
."	O
She	O
also	O
earned	O
two	O
Academy	MISC
Award	MISC
nominations	O
for	O
"	O
Little	MOVIE
Women	MOVIE
"	O
and	O
"	O
The	MOVIE
Age	MOVIE
of	MOVIE
Innocence	MOVIE
."	O


Winona	ACTOR
Ryder	ACTOR
as	O
Jo	PERSON
in	O
'	O
Little	MOVIE
Women	MOVIE
.'	O


But	O
don	O
't	O
expect	O
"	O
Black	MOVIE
Swan	MOVIE
"	O
to	O
be	O
her	O
swan	O
song	O
.	O
If	O
anything	O
,	O
Ryder	ACTOR
appears	O
to	O
be	O
gearing	O
up	O
for	O
the	O
next	O
phase	O
of	O
her	O
career	O
.	O


With	O
little	O
fanfare	O
,	O
Ryder	ACTOR
has	O
chosen	O
smaller	O
roles	O
or	O
smaller	O
films	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
--	O
and	O
Hollywood	CITY
has	O
taken	O
notice	O
.	O
Even	O
though	O
she	O
wasn	O
't	O
exactly	O
gone	O
--	O
she	O
only	O
lowered	O
her	O
profile	O
--	O
Ryder	ACTOR
is	O
definitely	O
back	O
.	O


"	O
She	O
can	O
act	O
.	O
She	O
can	O
do	O
drama	O
like	O
'	O
Black	MOVIE
Swan	MOVIE
'	O
and	O
comedy	O
like	O
'	O
The	MOVIE
Dilemma	MOVIE
,"	O
Lindsay	PERSON
Powers	PERSON
,	O
deputy	O
editor	O
for	O
The	ORGANIZATION
Hollywood	ORGANIZATION
Reporter.com	ORGANIZATION
told	O
ABCNews.com	ORGANIZATION
.	O


Winona	ACTOR
Ryder	ACTOR
as	O
Beth	PERSON
in	O
'	O
Black	MOVIE
Swan	MOVIE
.'	O


In	O
next	O
month	O
's	O
"	O
The	MOVIE
Dilemma	MOVIE
,"	O
a	O
Ron	PERSON
Howard	PERSON
comedy	O
,	O
Ryder	ACTOR
plays	O
Kevin	ACTOR
James	ACTOR
'	O
wife	O
,	O
who	O
is	O
caught	O
cheating	O
by	O
his	O
best	O
friend	O
,	O
Vince	ACTOR
Vaughn	ACTOR
.	O
The	O
two	O
movies	O
couldn	O
't	O
be	O
more	O
different	O
,	O
but	O
both	O
showcase	O
Ryder	ACTOR
's	O
wide	O
talent	O
.	O


=-DOCSTART-	O


ENTERTAINMENT	O


A	O
Controversial	O
,	O
Satiric	O
Look	O
at	O
Teen	O
Angst	O
:	O
Winona	ACTOR
Ryder	ACTOR
on	O
the	O
Road	O
to	O
a	O
Hot	O
Career	O
?	O


March	O
23	O
,	O
1989	O
|	O
By	O
PATRICK	PERSON
GOLDSTEIN	PERSON


Riding	O
shotgun	O
,	O
Winona	ACTOR
Ryder	ACTOR
kicked	O
her	O
feet	O
up	O
on	O
the	O
dashboard	O
and	O
pumped	O
up	O
the	O
volume	O
on	O
KROQ-FM	ORGANIZATION
,	O
ebulliently	O
crooning	O
to	O
the	O
Dead	PERSON
Milkmen	PERSON
's	O
"	O
Punk	MISC
Rock	MISC
Girl	MISC
."	O

It	O
was	O
time	O
for	O
her	O
favorite	O
pursuit	O
--	O
exploring	O
abandoned	O
houses	O
.	O
"	O
Quick	O
--	O
turn	O
right	O
,"	O
she	O
said	O
abruptly	O
as	O
the	O
car	O
approached	O
Sunset	O
and	O
Doheny	O
,	O
bumping	O
along	O
in	O
heavy	O
evening	O
traffic	O
.	O

"	O
It	O
should	O
be	O
around	O
here	O
somewhere	O
.	O
The	O
stories	O
about	O
this	O
house	O
sound	O
incredible	O
.	O
I	O
hear	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
great	O
spooky	O
old	O
place	O
."	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Naomi	ACTOR
Watts	ACTOR
is	O
a	O
film	O
actress	O
from	O
Australia	COUNTRY
.	O
Born	O
in	O
1968	O
in	O
England	COUNTRY
,	O
she	O
was	O
raised	O
in	O
England	COUNTRY
and	O
Whales	LOCATION
but	O
moved	O
to	O
Australia	COUNTRY
as	O
a	O
teenager	O
.	O
She	O
began	O
her	O
acting	O
career	O
in	O
commercials	O
on	O
Australian	O
television	O
and	O
later	O
in	O
soap	O
operas	O
.	O
She	O
also	O
did	O
work	O
in	O
Australian	O
independent	O
films	O
.	O


In	O
the	O
1990s	O
she	O
started	O
her	O
transition	O
from	O
Australia	COUNTRY
to	O
the	O
United	COUNTRY
States	COUNTRY
.	O
In	O
the	O
beginning	O
she	O
worked	O
in	O
low	O
budget	O
movies	O
,	O
but	O
after	O
several	O
years	O
,	O
she	O
started	O
to	O
get	O
better	O
roles	O
in	O
higher	O
quality	O
movies	O
.	O


Her	O
breakthrough	O
came	O
with	O
the	O
movie	O
,	O
Mulholland	MOVIE
Drive	MOVIE
.	O
Directed	O
by	O
David	PERSON
Lynch	PERSON
,	O
the	O
film	O
was	O
shown	O
at	O
the	O
Cannes	MISC
Film	MISC
Festival	MISC
which	O
lead	O
to	O
Naomi	ACTOR
Watts	ACTOR
being	O
named	O
best	O
actress	O
by	O
the	O
National	ORGANIZATION
Society	ORGANIZATION
of	ORGANIZATION
Film	ORGANIZATION
Critics	ORGANIZATION
.	O


After	O
this	O
she	O
started	O
to	O
be	O
noticed	O
by	O
a	O
wider	O
,	O
more	O
general	O
audience	O
.	O
She	O
starred	O
in	O
a	O
horror	O
film	O
called	O
,	O
"	O
The	MOVIE
Ring	MOVIE
,"	O
in	O
2002	O
.	O
In	O
2003	O
she	O
received	O
an	O
Academy	MISC
Award	MISC
nomination	O
for	O
her	O
work	O
in	O
"	O
21	MOVIE
Grams	MOVIE
."	O
In	O
2005	O
she	O
played	O
the	O
leading	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
remake	O
of	O
King	MOVIE
Kong	MOVIE
.	O


She	O
is	O
often	O
called	O
the	O
,	O
"	O
Queen	MISC
of	MISC
the	MISC
Remakes	MISC
,"	O
because	O
she	O
has	O
been	O
in	O
several	O
films	O
of	O
this	O
type	O
.	O
It	O
has	O
been	O
reported	O
that	O
she	O
is	O
now	O
working	O
on	O
a	O
remake	O
of	O
the	O
Alfred	PERSON
Hitchcock	PERSON
classic	O
,	O
"	O
The	MOVIE
Birds	MOVIE
,"	O
from	O
1963	O
.	O


see	O
less	O


=-DOCSTART-	O


Nicole	ACTOR
Kidman	ACTOR
is	O
the	O
best	O
actress	O
for	O
me	O
.	O
But	O
in	O
Australia	COUNTRY
I	O
think	O
she	O
just	O
ruined	O
her	O
talent	O
.	O
If	O
Nicole	ACTOR
had	O
not	O
starred	O
in	O
that	O
Australia	COUNTRY
,	O
that	O
movie	O
would	O
have	O
been	O
 	O
the	O
worst	O
.	O
It	O
will	O
be	O
 	O
even	O
really	O
difficult	O
just	O
to	O
name	O
what	O
type	O
of	O
the	O
movie	O
Austalia	COUNTRY
is	O
and	O
what	O
it	O
is	O
intended	O
.	O
Anyway	O
for	O
me	O
Nicole	ACTOR
is	O
the	O
best	O
 	O
and	O
she	O
is	O
my	O
favourite	O
.	O
Even	O
though	O
she	O
is	O
over	O
40	O
she	O
is	O
still	O
attractive	O
.	O


=-DOCSTART-	O


A	O
 	O
representative	O
 	O
for	O
CHRISTIAN	ACTOR
BALE	ACTOR
has	O
hit	O
back	O
at	O
rumours	O
the	O
star	O
's	O
alleged	O
hard-partying	O
ways	O
are	O
taking	O
a	O
toll	O
on	O
his	O
marriage	O
to	O
SIBI	PERSON
BLAZIC	PERSON
.	O


According	O
to	O
a	O
report	O
by	O
editors	O
at	O
America	NEWSPAPER
's	NEWSPAPER
Star	NEWSPAPER
magazine	O
,	O
the	O
Oscar-nominated	O
actor	O
has	O
been	O
hitting	O
the	O
Hollywood	CITY
party	O
scene	O
throughout	O
the	O
movie	O
industry	O
's	O
current	O
awards	O
season	O
.	O


The	O
magazine	O
claims	O
the	O
star	O
was	O
berated	O
by	O
film	O
mogul	O
Harvey	PERSON
Weinstein	PERSON
for	O
his	O
"	O
boorish	O
behaviour	O
"	O
at	O
the	O
 	O
SAG	MISC
Awards	MISC
afterparty	O
last	O
month	O
(	O
Jan11	O
),	O
causing	O
tension	O
with	O
his	O
wife	O
.	O


But	O
a	O
publicist	O
has	O
shot	O
down	O
the	O
reports	O
,	O
telling	O
Gossip.com	ORGANIZATION
that	O
 	O
The	MOVIE
Fighter	MOVIE
 	O
star	O
didn	O
't	O
even	O
attend	O
the	O
bash	O
.	O

Under-fire	O
Hollywood	CITY
star	O
Christian	ACTOR
Bale	ACTOR
is	O
a	O
"	O
wonderful	O
human	O
being	O
",...	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Edward	ACTOR
Norton	ACTOR
is	O
looking	O
to	O
use	O
people	O
's	O
passion	O
for	O
social	O
media	O
sites	O
for	O
a	O
good	O
cause	O
.	O
The	O
actor	O
recently	O
had	O
a	O
hand	O
in	O
creating	O
what	O
he	O
called	O
the	O
"	O
Facebook	ORGANIZATION
of	O
philanthropy	O
",	O
a	O
social	O
media	O
site	O
Crowdrise	ORGANIZATION
.	O


In	O
an	O
interview	O
with	O
CNN	ORGANIZATION
,	O
"	O
This	O
is	O
the	O
platform	O
where	O
you	O
plant	O
a	O
flag	O
and	O
say	O
this	O
is	O
who	O
I	O
am	O
,	O
as	O
defined	O
by	O
what	O
do	O
I	O
care	O
about	O
?	O
What	O
am	O
I	O
passionate	O
about	O
?	O
What	O
causes	O
do	O
I	O
support	O
?"	O
Norton	ACTOR
said	O
.	O
"	O
It	O
can	O
be	O
anything	O
.	O
We	O
don	O
't	O
try	O
to	O
suggest	O
to	O
you	O
what	O
you	O
ought	O
to	O
care	O
about	O
.	O
We	O
're	O
just	O
saying	O
,	O
find	O
your	O
own	O
way	O
."	O


On	O
the	O
site	O
,	O
people	O
create	O
page	O
and	O
can	O
start	O
fundraisers	O
to	O
ask	O
for	O
donations	O
from	O
friends	O
,	O
family	O
,	O
and	O
other	O
users	O
.	O
Norton	O
is	O
also	O
not	O
the	O
only	O
celebrity	O
on	O
the	O
site	O
.	O
Will	ACTOR
Ferrell	ACTOR
,	O
Paul	ACTOR
Rudd	ACTOR
,	O
Russell	ACTOR
Brand	ACTOR
,	O
and	O
Elizabeth	ACTOR
Banks	ACTOR
.	O


"	O
Look	O
,	O
you	O
've	O
got	O
a	O
generation	O
of	O
people	O
coming	O
along	O
who	O
are	O
going	O
to	O
form	O
their	O
own	O
new	O
relationship	O
with	O
the	O
idea	O
of	O
supporting	O
the	O
causes	O
that	O
they	O
care	O
about	O
or	O
changing	O
the	O
world	O
,"	O
Norton	ACTOR
said	O
in	O
his	O
interview	O
.	O
"	O
And	O
these	O
people	O
are	O
not	O
going	O
to	O
do	O
it	O
the	O
way	O
our	O
parents	O
do	O
it	O
."	O


On	O
the	O
site	O
members	O
can	O
also	O
earn	O
points	O
and	O
win	O
prizes	O
when	O
their	O
fundraising	O
efforts	O
reach	O
certain	O
benchmarks	O
.	O
"	O
If	O
you	O
don	O
't	O
give	O
back	O
,	O
no	O
one	O
will	O
like	O
you	O
.	O
That	O
is	O
our	O
core	O
philosophy	O
.	O
We	O
're	O
a	O
bunch	O
of	O
dorks	O
,"	O
Norton	ACTOR
told	O
CNN	ORGANIZATION
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Mark	PERSON
Sanchez	PERSON
Discusses	O
Boogergate	O
on	O
SiriusXM	MISC

What	O
was	O
he	O
thinking	O
and	O
what	O
will	O
the	O
payback	O
be	O
?	O
Watch	O
New	TEAM
York	TEAM
Jets	TEAM
quarterback	O
,	O
Mark	ATHLETE
Sanchez	ATHLETE
,	O
admit	O
to	O
wiping	O
a	O
booger	O
on	O
teammate	O
Mark	ATHLETE
Brunell	ATHLETE
when	O
he	O
stopped	O
by	O
The	MISC
Covino	MISC
&	MISC
Rich	MISC
Show	MISC
during	O
Super	MISC
Bowl	MISC
week	O
in	O
Dallas	CITY
.	O
For	O
a	O
free	O
trial	O
and	O
to	O
learn	O
more	O
about	O
Covino	MISC
&	MISC
Rich	MISC
,	O
visit	O
...	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


The	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
is	O
a	O
70-seat	O
,	O
twin-engine	O
jet	O
airliner	O
produced	O
by	O
Fokker	ORGANIZATION
as	O
a	O
smaller	O
version	O
of	O
the	O
100-seat	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
100	AIRPLANE
jetliner	O
.	O
With	O
its	O
first	O
flight	O
in	O
1994	O
,	O
47	O
aircraft	O
,	O
plus	O
one	O
prototype	O
,	O
have	O
been	O
manufactured	O
and	O
most	O
are	O
still	O
in	O
active	O
service	O
with	O
airlines	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
especially	O
European	O
airlines	O
.	O


Design	O
and	O
development	O


The	O
Fokker	ORGANIZATION
company	O
of	O
the	O
Netherlands	COUNTRY
started	O
to	O
develop	O
the	O
airliner	O
in	O
November	O
1992	O
with	O
an	O
aim	O
to	O
replace	O
its	O
aging	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
F28	AIRPLANE
airliner	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
more	O
modern	O
and	O
fuel	O
efficient	O
aircraft	O
.	O
The	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
's	O
first	O
flight	O
occurred	O
on	O
April	O
4	O
,	O
1993	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
base	O
at	O
Woensdrecht	CITY
in	O
southern	O
Netherlands	COUNTRY
,	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
duration	O
of	O
three	O
hours	O
.	O
Following	O
its	O
first	O
flight	O
,	O
the	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
was	O
flown	O
to	O
Granada	CITY
and	O
Spain	COUNTRY
,	O
where	O
many	O
hours	O
were	O
realised	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
obtain	O
the	O
certification	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
1994	O
.	O
The	O
first	O
production	O
aircraft	O
first	O
flew	O
in	O
July	O
1994	O
.	O
Certification	O
was	O
granted	O
on	O
October	O
14	O
,	O
1994	O
,	O
while	O
the	O
first	O
delivery	O
of	O
a	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
to	O
a	O
customer	O
,	O
Ford	ORGANIZATION
Motor	ORGANIZATION
Company	ORGANIZATION
(	O
in	O
an	O
"	O
Executive	AIRPLANE
Jet	AIRPLANE
"	O
configuration	O
),	O
occurred	O
later	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
month	O
.	O


The	O
development	O
of	O
the	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
was	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
need	O
of	O
some	O
airlines	O
for	O
which	O
the	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
50	AIRPLANE
or	O
ATR	AIRPLANE
42	AIRPLANE
were	O
too	O
small	O
and	O
Boeing	AIRPLANE
737	AIRPLANE
or	O
MD-80	AIRPLANE
too	O
large	O
for	O
their	O
needs	O
.	O
The	O
development	O
consisted	O
in	O
cutting	O
various	O
sections	O
of	O
the	O
fuselage	O
of	O
the	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
100	AIRPLANE
,	O
removing	O
4.62	O
|	O
m	O
|	O
ft	O
of	O
the	O
plane	O
's	O
total	O
length	O
but	O
keeping	O
wings	O
and	O
tail	O
.	O
With	O
these	O
specifications	O
,	O
total	O
capacity	O
is	O
80	O
passengers	O
,	O
70	O
|	O
in	O
|	O
cm	O
the	O
U.S.	COUNTRY
due	O
more	O
so	O
to	O
meet	O
"	O
scope	O
clause	O
"	O
requirement	O
than	O
to	O
any	O
Federal	ORGANIZATION
Aviation	ORGANIZATION
Administration	ORGANIZATION
(	O
FAA	ORGANIZATION
)	O
certification	O
.	O


The	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
is	O
powered	O
by	O
two	O
Rolls-Royce	PRODUCT
Tay	PRODUCT
620	PRODUCT
turbofans	O
placed	O
at	O
the	O
back	O
of	O
the	O
fuselage	O
with	O
61.6	O
kN	O
(	O
13,849	O
lb	O
)	O
of	O
thrust	O
.	O
The	O
weight	O
varies	O
from	O
22673	O
|	O
kg	O
|	O
lb	O
when	O
empty	O
to	O
41730	O
|	O
kg	O
|	O
lb	O
at	O
maximum	O
takeoff	O
weight	O
(	O
MTOW	O
).	O
An	O
air	O
brake	O
on	O
the	O
70	O
's	O
tail	O
section	O
–	O
similar	O
to	O
that	O
found	O
on	O
the	O
BAe	AIRPLANE
146	AIRPLANE
–	O
which	O
allows	O
it	O
to	O
conform	O
with	O
the	O
5.5	O
°	O
glide	O
slope	O
at	O
London	AIRPORT
City	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
.	O
Its	O
avionics	O
suite	O
is	O
similar	O
to	O
the	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
100	AIRPLANE
.	O


Most	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
aircraft	O
were	O
delivered	O
for	O
service	O
in	O
Europe	LOCATION
,	O
but	O
in	O
1995	O
two	O
aircraft	O
were	O
delivered	O
to	O
America	ORGANIZATION
West	ORGANIZATION
Express	ORGANIZATION
as	O
part	O
of	O
an	O
effort	O
to	O
try	O
to	O
introduce	O
the	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
to	O
the	O
United	COUNTRY
States	COUNTRY
.	O
Although	O
the	O
earlier	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
100	AIRPLANE
did	O
moderately	O
well	O
in	O
the	O
United	COUNTRY
States	COUNTRY
with	O
orders	O
from	O
American	ORGANIZATION
Airlines	ORGANIZATION
and	O
USAir	ORGANIZATION
(	O
now	O
US	ORGANIZATION
Airways	ORGANIZATION
),	O
only	O
two	O
aircraft	O
were	O
delivered	O
for	O
service	O
in	O
the	O
United	COUNTRY
States	COUNTRY
.	O

Fokker	ORGANIZATION
's	O
March	O
1996	O
bankruptcy	O
ended	O
any	O
hopes	O
of	O
further	O
production	O
for	O
the	O
U.S.	COUNTRY
market	O
;	O
the	O
two	O
America	ORGANIZATION
West	ORGANIZATION
Express	ORGANIZATION
aircraft	O
became	O
an	O
expensive	O
subfleet	O
and	O
were	O
sent	O
to	O
Europe	LOCATION
in	O
1997	O
,	O
ending	O
the	O
very	O
short	O
tenure	O
of	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
operation	O
in	O
the	O
United	COUNTRY
States	COUNTRY
.	O


The	O
last	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
was	O
delivered	O
in	O
April	O
1997	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
production	O
line	O
closed	O
following	O
Fokker	ORGANIZATION
's	O
bankruptcy	O
the	O
previous	O
year	O
.	O
Over	O
the	O
70	O
's	O
short	O
production	O
life	O
,	O
47	O
were	O
built	O
.	O
Although	O
official	O
production	O
of	O
the	O
Fokker	AIRPLANE
70	AIRPLANE
is	O
completed	O
,	O
Rekkof	MISC
("	O
Fokker	ORGANIZATION
"	O
spelt	O
backwards	O
)	O
has	O
...	O

see	O
less	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Gnat	AIRPLANE

The	O
Folland	AIRPLANE
Gnat	AIRPLANE
was	O
a	O
small	O
,	O
swept-wing	O
British	O
subsonic	O
jet	O
trainer	O
and	O
light	O
fighter	O
aircraft	O
developed	O
for	O
the	O
Royal	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
,	O
and	O
flown	O
extensively	O
by	O
the	O
Indian	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
.	O

It	O
was	O
designed	O
by	O
W.E.W.	PERSON
Petter	PERSON
,	O
and	O
first	O
flew	O
in	O
1955	O
.	O
Its	O
design	O
allowed	O
its	O
construction	O
without	O
specialised	O
tools	O
by	O
countries	O
not	O
highly	O
industrialised	O
.[	O
1	O
][	O
2	O
]	O
Although	O
never	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
fighter	O
by	O
the	O
Royal	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
(	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
),	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
T.	AIRPLANE
1	AIRPLANE
trainer	O
variant	O
was	O
widely	O
used	O
.	O
The	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
became	O
well	O
known	O
as	O
the	O
mount	O
for	O
the	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
Red	ORGANIZATION
Arrows	ORGANIZATION
aerobatic	ORGANIZATION
team	ORGANIZATION
.	O


The	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
also	O
achieved	O
export	O
success	O
,	O
particularly	O
with	O
India	COUNTRY
,	O
the	O
largest	O
foreign	O
operator	O
who	O
manufactured	O
the	O
aircraft	O
under	O
licence	O
.	O
India	COUNTRY
then	O
developed	O
the	O
HAL	AIRPLANE
Ajeet	AIRPLANE
,	O
a	O
modified	O
and	O
improved	O
variant	O
.	O

The	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
was	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
W.E.W.	PERSON
"	PERSON
Teddy	PERSON
"	PERSON
Petter	PERSON
,	O
a	O
British	O
aircraft	O
designer	O
formerly	O
of	O
Westland	ORGANIZATION
Aircraft	ORGANIZATION
and	O
English	ORGANIZATION
Electric	ORGANIZATION
.	O

Designed	O
to	O
meet	O
the	O
1952	O
Operational	MISC
Requirement	MISC
OR.303	MISC
calling	O
for	O
a	O
lightweight	O
fighter	O
,	O
Petter	PERSON
believed	O
that	O
a	O
small	O
,	O
simple	O
fighter	O
would	O
offer	O
the	O
advantages	O
of	O
low	O
purchase	O
and	O
operational	O
costs	O
.	O
New	O
lightweight	O
turbojet	O
engines	O
that	O
were	O
being	O
developed	O
enabled	O
the	O
concept	O
to	O
take	O
shape	O
.[	O
1	O
]	O
Petter	PERSON
's	O
first	O
design	O
resulted	O
in	O
the	O
private	O
venture	O
Folland	AIRPLANE
Midge	AIRPLANE
which	O
had	O
a	O
short	O
lifespan	O
,	O
but	O
served	O
as	O
a	O
proof-of-concept	O
design	O
.	O


The	O
Midge	AIRPLANE
first	O
flew	O
on	O
11	O
August	O
1954	O
but	O
was	O
destroyed	O
in	O
a	O
crash	O
on	O
20	O
September	O
1955	O
.	O
The	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
,	O
being	O
developed	O
in	O
parallel	O
with	O
the	O
Midge	AIRPLANE
,	O
was	O
an	O
improved	O
version	O
of	O
the	O
original	O
fighter	O
design	O
,	O
differentiated	O
by	O
larger	O
air	O
intakes	O
and	O
provision	O
for	O
a	O
30	PRODUCT
 	PRODUCT
mm	PRODUCT
Aden	PRODUCT
cannon	PRODUCT
in	O
each	O
intake	O
lip	O
.[	O
3	O
]	O


Gnat	AIRPLANE
F.	AIRPLANE
1	AIRPLANE
single	O
seat	O
fighter	O
variant	O
at	O
the	O
1957	O
Paris	MISC
Air	MISC
Salon	MISC


One	O
of	O
the	O
hallmarks	O
of	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
's	O
design	O
was	O
its	O
compact	O
size	O
.	O
However	O
,	O
to	O
achieve	O
such	O
a	O
size	O
,	O
its	O
systems	O
were	O
closely	O
packed	O
,	O
making	O
maintenance	O
more	O
difficult	O
.	O

Some	O
of	O
its	O
systems	O
were	O
not	O
noted	O
for	O
their	O
reliability	O
and	O
the	O
aircraft	O
suffered	O
from	O
high	O
operating	O
costs	O
.	O
There	O
were	O
also	O
concerns	O
that	O
its	O
cockpit	O
was	O
cramped	O
and	O
obstructed	O
the	O
instructor	O
's	O
forward	O
visibility	O
.[	O
4	O
]	O
Furthermore	O
,	O
the	O
limited	O
weapons	O
load	O
and	O
reduced	O
fuel	O
capacity	O
–	O
both	O
designed	O
to	O
reduce	O
overall	O
kerb	O
weight	O
–	O
meant	O
that	O
it	O
could	O
not	O
operate	O
for	O
protracted	O
periods	O
.	O

Despite	O
the	O
shortcomings	O
,	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
and	O
the	O
Midge	AIRPLANE
were	O
praised	O
by	O
the	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
evaluation	O
and	O
the	O
test	O
pilots	O
in	O
the	O
1955	O
Gnat	ORGANIZATION
Flight	ORGANIZATION
Development	ORGANIZATION
Team	ORGANIZATION
that	O
included	O
a	O
pilot	O
from	O
India	COUNTRY
.	O
The	O
lower	O
purchase	O
price	O
of	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
,	O
its	O
compact	O
dimensions	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
"	O
good	O
press	O
"	O
for	O
the	O
aircraft	O
in	O
air	O
shows	O
,	O
were	O
among	O
the	O
factors	O
that	O
prompted	O
a	O
spurt	O
in	O
its	O
export	O
sales	O
.[	O
5	O
]	O

An	O
operational	O
Folland	AIRPLANE
Gnat	AIRPLANE
T.	AIRPLANE
1	AIRPLANE
of	O
No.4	UNIVERSITY
Flying	UNIVERSITY
Training	UNIVERSITY
School	UNIVERSITY
at	O
RAF	LOCATION
Valley	LOCATION
in	O
1967	O


Gnat	AIRPLANE
T.	AIRPLANE
1	AIRPLANE
on	O
display	O
in	O
2009	O


Although	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
was	O
evaluated	O
by	O
the	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
in	O
1958	O
as	O
a	O
possible	O
DH	AIRPLANE
Venom	AIRPLANE
replacement	O
,	O
the	O
Hawker	AIRPLANE
Hunter	AIRPLANE
was	O
the	O
eventual	O
winner	O
of	O
the	O
fly-off	O
competition	O
.	O
Although	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
interest	O
waned	O
in	O
its	O
possible	O
use	O
as	O
a	O
fighter	O
,	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
was	O
modified	O
to	O
meet	O
the	O
1957	O
Trainer	MISC
Specification	MISC
T.	MISC
185D	MISC
that	O
called	O
for	O
an	O
advanced	O
two-seat	O
trainer	O
that	O
could	O
transition	O
pilots	O
between	O
the	O
current	O
DH	AIRPLANE
Vampire	AIRPLANE
T	AIRPLANE
11	AIRPLANE
and	O
operational	O
fighters	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
English	AIRPLANE
Electric	AIRPLANE
Lightning	AIRPLANE
.	O
After	O
review	O
of	O
Folland	PERSON
's	O
proposals	O
,	O
an	O
initial	O
contract	O
for	O
14	O
modified	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
trainers	O
was	O
issued	O
in	O
7	O
January	O
1958	O
.[	O
6	O
]	O
The	O
Folland	AIRPLANE
Fo.144	AIRPLANE
Gnat	AIRPLANE
Trainer	AIRPLANE
served	O
in	O
the	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
with	O
the	O
designation	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
T	AIRPLANE
Mk	AIRPLANE
1	AIRPLANE
.	O
It	O
was	O
notable	O
as	O
the	O
demonstration	O
aircraft	O
of	O
the	O
Red	ORGANIZATION
Arrows	ORGANIZATION
aerobatic	ORGANIZATION
display	ORGANIZATION
team	ORGANIZATION
between	O
1964	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
team	O
was	O
formed	O
,	O
and	O
1979	O
,	O
when	O
it	O
was	O
replaced	O
by	O
the	O
Hawk	AIRPLANE
.	O


When	O
the	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
sold	O
off	O
its	O
Gnats	O
,	O
many	O
were	O
bought	O
by	O
private	O
collectors	O
and	O
some	O
subsequently	O
appeared	O
in	O
the	O
1991	O
comedy	O
film	O
Hot	MOVIE
Shots	MOVIE
!.	O


ex-RAF	O
Folland	AIRPLANE
Gnat	AIRPLANE
T.	AIRPLANE
1	AIRPLANE
during	O
a	O
display	O
at	O
Kemble	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
in	O
2008	O
.	O
This	O
aircraft	O
is	O
painted	O
in	O
the	O
colours	O
of	O
a	O
former	O
RAF	ORGANIZATION
display	O
team	O
,	O
the	O
Yellowjacks	MISC
.	O

The	O
Finnish	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
received	O
the	O
first	O
of	O
its	O
13	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
on	O
30	O
July	O
1958	O
.	O
It	O
was	O
soon	O
found	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
problematic	O
aircraft	O
in	O
service	O
and	O
required	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
ground	O
maintenance	O
.	O
Finland	COUNTRY
considered	O
licence	O
manufacturing	O
the	O
aircraft	O
but	O
decided	O
not	O
to	O
.	O
On	O
31	O
July	O
1958	O
,	O
the	O
Finnish	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
Major	ORGANIZATION
Lauri	PERSON
Pekuri	PERSON
broke	O
the	O
sound	O
barrier	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
Finland	COUNTRY
at	O
Lake	LAKE
Luonetjärvi	LAKE
with	O
a	O
Folland	AIRPLANE
Gnat	AIRPLANE
.[	O
7	O
]	O


All	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
were	O
grounded	O
on	O
26	O
August	O
1958	O
for	O
six	O
months	O
after	O
the	O
destruction	O
of	O
GN-102	AIRPLANE
due	O
to	O
a	O
technical	O
error	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
aircraft	O
soon	O
became	O
the	O
subject	O
of	O
severe	O
criticism	O
.	O
Three	O
other	O
aircraft	O
were	O
also	O
destroyed	O
in	O
other	O
accidents	O
.	O
The	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
were	O
removed	O
from	O
active	O
service	O
in	O
1972	O
when	O
the	O
Häme	AIRPLANE
Wing	AIRPLANE
moved	O
to	O
Rovaniemi	CITY
,	O
and	O
when	O
the	O
new	O
Saab	AIRPLANE
35	AIRPLANE
Draken	AIRPLANE
s	O
were	O
taken	O
into	O
use	O
.	O

Serving	O
primarily	O
with	O
the	O
Indian	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
,	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
is	O
credited	O
by	O
many	O
independent	O
and	O
Indian	O
sources	O
to	O
have	O
shot	O
down	O
seven	O
Pakistani	AIRPLANE
Canadair	AIRPLANE
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s	O
(	O
licence-built	O
F-86	AIRPLANE
s	O
)	O
in	O
the	O
1965	O
war	O
.[	O
8	O
][	O
9	O
][	O
10	O
]	O
The	O
Pakistan	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
(	O
PAF	ORGANIZATION
)	O
claims	O
only	O
three	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
victories	O
over	O
F-86	AIRPLANE
s	O
in	O
air	O
to	O
air	O
combat	O
,[	O
11	O
]	O
while	O
two	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
were	O
downed	O
by	O
PAF	ORGANIZATION
fighters	O
.	O
During	O
the	O
initial	O
phase	O
of	O
the	O
1965	O
war	O
,	O
an	O
IAF	AIRPLANE
Gnat	AIRPLANE
,	O
piloted	O
by	O
Squadron	O
Leader	O
Brij	PERSON
Pal	PERSON
Singh	PERSON
Sikand	PERSON
,	O
landed	O
at	O
an	O
abandoned	O
Pakistani	O
airstrip	O
at	O
Pasrur	CITY
and	O
was	O
captured	O
by	O
the	O
PAF	ORGANIZATION
.	O
Two	O
Lockheed	AIRPLANE
F-104	AIRPLANE
Starfighter	AIRPLANE
s	O
forced	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
down	O
.	O

[	O
12	O
][	O
13	O
]	O
[	O
N	O
1	O
][	O
14	O
]	O
This	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
is	O
displayed	O
as	O
a	O
war	O
trophy	O
in	O
the	O
Pakistan	MISC
Air	MISC
Force	MISC
Museum	MISC
,	O
Karachi	CITY
.	O
After	O
the	O
ceasefire	O
,	O
one	O
Pakistani	O
Cessna	AIRPLANE
O-1	AIRPLANE
was	O
shot	O
down	O
on	O
16	O
December	O
1965	O
by	O
a	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
.[	O
15	O
]	O

The	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
were	O
used	O
again	O
by	O
India	COUNTRY
in	O
the	O
Bangladesh	MISC
Liberation	MISC
War	MISC
against	O
Pakistan	COUNTRY
.[	O
16	O
][	O
17	O
]	O
The	O
most	O
notable	O
action	O
was	O
the	O
Battle	MISC
of	MISC
Boyra	MISC
where	O
the	O
first	O
dogfights	O
over	O
East	COUNTRY
Pakistan	COUNTRY
(	O
Bangladesh	COUNTRY
)	O
took	O
place	O
.	O
The	O
IAF	AIRPLANE
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
downed	O
two	O
PAF	AIRPLANE
Canadair	AIRPLANE
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s	O
in	O
minutes	O
and	O
badly	O
damaged	O
one	O
.	O
The	O
Pakistan	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
claims	O
that	O
one	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
was	O
shot	O
down,which	O
was	O
proved	O
incorrect	O
.	O
Another	O
notable	O
dogfight	O
involving	O
a	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
was	O
over	O
Srinagar	AIRPORT
airfield	AIRPORT
where	O
a	O
lone	O
Indian	O
pilot	O
held	O
out	O
against	O
six	O
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s	O
,[	O
18	O
]	O
scoring	O
hits	O
on	O
two	O
of	O
the	O
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
,[	O
19	O
][	O
20	O
]	O
before	O
being	O
overwhelmed	O
.	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
pilot	O
Nirmal	PERSON
Jit	PERSON
Singh	PERSON
Sekhon	PERSON
was	O
posthumously	O
honoured	O
with	O
Param	MISC
Vir	MISC
Chakra	MISC
(	O
India	COUNTRY
's	O
highest	O
gallantry	O
award	O
),	O
becoming	O
the	O
only	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
IAF	ORGANIZATION
to	O
be	O
given	O
the	O
award	O
.	O


By	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
1971	O
,	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
proved	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
frustrating	O
opponent	O
for	O
the	O
technically	O
superior	O
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s	O
and	O
had	O
lived	O
up	O
to	O
its	O
Indian	ORGANIZATION
Air	ORGANIZATION
Force	ORGANIZATION
nickname	O
of	O
"	O
Sabre	MISC
Slayers	MISC
"	O
since	O
all	O
its	O
combat	O
"	O
kills	O
"	O
during	O
the	O
two	O
wars	O
were	O
against	O
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s.	O
[	O
21	O
][	O
22	O
]	O
The	O
Canadair	AIRPLANE
Sabre	AIRPLANE
Mk	AIRPLANE
6	AIRPLANE
was	O
widely	O
regarded	O
as	O
the	O
best	O
dogfighter	O
of	O
its	O
era	O
.[	O
8	O
][	O
23	O
][	O
24	O
]	O

Tactics	O
called	O
for	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
taking	O
on	O
the	O
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s	O
in	O
the	O
vertical	O
arena	O
,	O
where	O
the	O
Sabre	AIRPLANE
s	O
were	O
at	O
a	O
disadvantage	O
.	O
Moreover	O
,	O
because	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
was	O
lightweight	O
and	O
compact	O
in	O
shape	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
hard	O
to	O
see	O
,	O
especially	O
at	O
the	O
low	O
levels	O
where	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
dogfights	O
took	O
place	O
.[	O
10	O
]	O
Apart	O
from	O
air	O
defence	O
operations	O
,	O
the	O
aircraft	O
performed	O
multiple	O
roles	O
in	O
the	O
Bangladesh	MISC
Liberation	MISC
War	MISC
,	O
being	O
used	O
in	O
anti-shipping	O
operations	O
,	O
ground	O
attack	O
,	O
bomber	O
/	O
transport	O
escort	O
and	O
close	O
air	O
support	O
with	O
devastating	O
effects	O
on	O
the	O
PAF	ORGANIZATION
.[	O
16	O
][	O
17	O
]	O

The	O
success	O
of	O
the	O
indigenously	O
produced	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
s	O
against	O
the	O
more	O
sophisticated	O
Pakistani-flown	O
aircraft	O
was	O
viewed	O
as	O
a	O
significant	O
achievement	O
.[	O
25	O
]	O

The	O
IAF	ORGANIZATION
were	O
impressed	O
by	O
the	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
's	O
performance	O
in	O
the	O
two	O
wars	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
aircraft	O
had	O
problems	O
including	O
hydraulics	O
and	O
unreliable	O
control	O
systems	O
.	O
To	O
address	O
these	O
issues	O
,	O
the	O
IAF	ORGANIZATION
issued	O
a	O
requirement	O
for	O
an	O
improved	O
"	O
Gnat	AIRPLANE
II	AIRPLANE
"	O
in	O
1972	O
,	O
at	O
first	O
specifying	O
that	O
the	O
new	O
version	O
was	O
to	O
be	O
optimized	O
as	O
an	O
interceptor	O
,	O
but	O
then	O
expanding	O
the	O
specification	O
to	O
include	O
the	O
ground-attack	O
role	O
.	O
Over	O
175	O
of	O
the	O
Hindustan	ORGANIZATION
Aeronautics	ORGANIZATION
Limited	ORGANIZATION
-	O
built	O
licenced	O
version	O
,	O
the	O
Ajeet	AIRPLANE
("	O
Unconquerable	MISC
"),	O
were	O
produced	O
in	O
Bangalore	CITY
,	O
while	O
about	O
40	O
were	O
purchased	O
directly	O
from	O
Folland	ORGANIZATION
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


The	O
Americas	MISC
Best	MISC
Value	MISC
Inn	MISC
of	MISC
Montgomery	MISC
,	O
AL	LOCATION
,	O
is	O
an	O
affordable	O
3-story	O
,	O
exterior	O
corridor	O
hotel	O
.	O


Americas	MISC
Best	MISC
Value	MISC
Inn	MISC
has	O
everything	O
a	O
traveler	O
,	O
corporate	O
or	O
leisure	O
,	O
can	O
ask	O
for	O
:	O
plenty	O
of	O
amenities	O
including	O
an	O
outdoor	O
pool	O
and	O
on	O
site	O
laundry	O
facilities	O
,	O
great	O
location	O
and	O
a	O
very	O
affordable	O
price	O
!	O
Located	O
a	O
mere	O
10	O
minutes	O
from	O
downtown	O
Montgomery	CITY
and	O
attractions	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
Hank	MISC
Williams	MISC
Museum	MISC
and	O
the	O
Montgomery	MISC
Zoo	MISC
. 	O

The	O
hotel	O
is	O
also	O
just	O
4	O
miles	O
from	O
Montgomery	AIRPORT
Regional	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
and	O
30	O
minutes	O
from	O
the	O
Victoryland	LOCATION
Greyhound	LOCATION
Racing	LOCATION
Park	LOCATION
.	O


We	O
start	O
your	O
day	O
right	O
with	O
a	O
fresh	O
complimentary	O
continental	O
breakfast	O
and	O
a	O
complimentary	O
newspaper	O
. 	O
The	O
hotel	O
's	O
staff	O
will	O
go	O
the	O
extra	O
mile	O
to	O
assure	O
a	O
pleasant	O
stay	O
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Have	O
you	O
used	O
Charlotte	AIRPORT
Douglas	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
?	O
Love	O
it	O
?	O
Hate	O
it	O
?	O
We	O
welcome	O
your	O
reviews	O
,	O
questions	O
,	O

or	O
comments	O
about	O
the	O
airport	O
.	O
Your	O
feedback	O
,	O
if	O
suitable	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
published	O
on	O
this	O
page	O
for	O
the	O
benefit	O
of	O
other	O
users	O
.	O



Charlotte	AIRPORT
Douglas	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
(	O
IATA	MISC
:	O
CLT	AIRPORT
,	O
ICAO	ORGANIZATION
:	O
KCLT	AIRPORT
,	O
FAA	ORGANIZATION
LID	ORGANIZATION
:	O
CLT	AIRPORT
)	O
is	O
a	O
mid-size	O
international	O
airport	O
located	O
in	O
Charlotte	CITY
,	O
North	LOCATION
Carolina	LOCATION
.	O


Charlotte	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
is	O
the	O
hub	O
of	O
stock	O
car	O
racing	O
,	O
with	O
major	O
races	O
being	O
held	O
at	O
nearby	O
Lowe	LOCATION
's	LOCATION
Motor	LOCATION
Speedway	LOCATION
,	O
considered	O
by	O
most	O
fans	O
and	O
participants	O
in	O
the	O
sport	O
to	O
be	O
NASCAR	ORGANIZATION
's	O
'	O
home	O
track	O
'.	O
A	O
vast	O
majority	O
of	O
NASCAR	ORGANIZATION
teams	O
and	O
race	O
shops	O
are	O
located	O
within	O
40	O
miles	O
of	O
Charlotte	CITY
,	O
and	O
most	O
NASCAR	ORGANIZATION
drivers	O
maintain	O
a	O
residence	O
in	O
or	O
near	O
the	O
city	O
.	O
Seventy-three	O
percent	O
of	O
American	O
motorsports	O
employees	O
are	O
based	O
within	O
two	O
hours	O
of	O
downtown	O
Charlotte	CITY
.	O
The	O
NASCAR	MISC
Hall	MISC
of	MISC
Fame	MISC
is	O
set	O
to	O
open	O
in	O
Charlotte	CITY
in	O
early	O
2009	O
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


O	AIRPORT
'Hare	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
(	O
IATA	ORGANIZATION
:	O
ORD	AIRPORT
,	O
ICAO	ORGANIZATION
:	O
KORD	AIRPORT
,	O
FAA	ORGANIZATION
LID	ORGANIZATION
:	O
ORD	AIRPORT
),	O
also	O
known	O
simply	O
as	O
O	AIRPORT
'Hare	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
,	O
is	O
an	O
airport	O
located	O
in	O
Chicago	CITY
,	O
Illinois	LOCATION
,	O
17	O
miles	O
(	O
27	O
km	O
)	O
northwest	O
of	O
the	O
Chicago	CITY
Loop	O
.	O
It	O
is	O
the	O
largest	O
hub	O
of	O
United	ORGANIZATION
Airlines	ORGANIZATION
and	O
the	O
second-largest	O
hub	O
of	O
American	ORGANIZATION
Airlines	ORGANIZATION
.	O


O	AIRPORT
'Hare	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
is	O
the	O
second	O
busiest	O
airport	O
in	O
both	O
the	O
United	COUNTRY
States	COUNTRY
and	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
with	O
69,353,654	O
passengers	O
passing	O
through	O
the	O
airport	O
in	O
2008	O
.	O


O	AIRPORT
'Hare	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
was	O
voted	O
the	O
"	O
Best	O
Airport	O
in	O
North	LOCATION
America	LOCATION
"	O
for	O
10	O
years	O
,	O
by	O
readers	O
of	O
the	O
U.S.	COUNTRY
Edition	O
of	O
Business	NEWSPAPER
Traveler	NEWSPAPER
Magazine	NEWSPAPER
(	O
1998	O
-	O
2003	O
)	O
and	O
Global	NEWSPAPER
Traveler	NEWSPAPER
Magazine	NEWSPAPER
(	O
2004	O
-	O
2007	O
).	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


As	O
a	O
national	O
capital	O
and	O
a	O
regional	O
crossroads	O
of	O
commerce	O
and	O
tourism	O
,	O
Bangkok	CITY
has	O
long	O
supported	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
busiest	O
airports	O
—	O
currently	O
15th	O
in	O
passenger	O
volume	O
.	O

In	O
designing	O
Suvarnabhumi	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
,	O
the	O
city	O
's	O
new	O
international	O
hub	O
,	O
Chicago	CITY
-	O
based	O
architects	O
Murphy	PERSON
/	O
Jahn	PERSON
realized	O
from	O
the	O
outset	O
that	O
the	O
passenger	O
terminal	O
would	O
need	O
to	O
accommodate	O
a	O
vast	O
scale	O
of	O
operations	O
and	O
express	O
its	O
pivotal	O
importance	O
to	O
Thailand	COUNTRY
.	O
Suvarnabhumi	AIRPORT
,	O
meaning	O
"	O
land	O
of	O
gold	O
,"	O
has	O
a	O
capacity	O
of	O
45	O
million	O
passengers	O
annually	O
,	O
with	O
56	O
jetway	O
(	O
plus	O
64	O
bus-to-plane	O
)	O
gates	O
,	O
served	O
by	O
some	O
6	O
million	O
square	O
feet	O
of	O
floor	O
area	O
.	O
Planned	O
subsequent	O
phases	O
will	O
increase	O
its	O
capacity	O
to	O
100	O
million	O
passengers	O
per	O
year	O
.	O


Photography	O
:	O
©	O
Rainer	PERSON
Viertlboeck	PERSON
(	O
top	O
);	O
Courtesy	O
,	O
John	PERSON
Morris	PERSON
Dixon	PERSON
(	O
above	O
).	O


This	O
view	O
over	O
the	O
Arrivals	O
area	O
shows	O
an	O
accretion	O
of	O
sales	O
and	O
info	O
booths	O
encroaching	O
on	O
the	O
architecture	O
,	O
where	O
architect	O
Murphy	PERSON
/	O
Jahn	PERSON
 	O
envisioned	O
a	O
generous	O
space	O
,	O
separated	O
from	O
the	O
exterior	O
only	O
by	O
a	O
wall	O
of	O
clear	O
glass	O
(	O
above	O
).	O


Rate	O
this	O
project	O
:	O


Based	O
on	O
what	O
you	O
have	O
seen	O
and	O
read	O
about	O
this	O
project	O
,	O
how	O
would	O
you	O
grade	O
it	O
?	O
Use	O
the	O
stars	O
below	O
to	O
indicate	O
your	O
assessment	O
,	O
five	O
stars	O
being	O
the	O
highest	O
rating	O
.	O


-----	O
Advertising	O
-----	O


The	O
design	O
,	O
winner	O
of	O
an	O
invited	O
international	O
competition	O
held	O
in	O
1994	O
,	O
presents	O
a	O
powerful	O
image	O
:	O
a	O
lofty	O
pavilion	O
under	O
a	O
gigantic	O
canopy	O
hovering	O
over	O
an	O
area	O
exceeding	O
1.2	O
million	O
square	O
feet	O
,	O
with	O
tubular	O
concourses	O
extending	O
from	O
it	O
.	O
Though	O
the	O
concourses	O
feature	O
the	O
kind	O
of	O
emphatically	O
repeating	O
structural	O
modules	O
that	O
characterize	O
entire	O
recent	O
air	O
terminals	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
Norman	PERSON
Foster	PERSON
's	O
in	O
Hong	CITY
Kong	CITY
or	O
Richard	PERSON
Rogers	PERSON
's	O
in	O
Madrid	CITY
,	O
Suvarnabhumi	AIRPORT
rises	O
to	O
a	O
dominant	O
central	O
volume	O
.	O
Like	O
those	O
other	O
major	O
airports	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
Bangkok	CITY
's	O
could	O
not	O
have	O
been	O
realized	O
without	O
feats	O
of	O
structural	O
engineering	O
.	O
It	O
also	O
demanded	O
significant	O
rethinking	O
of	O
interior	O
climate	O
control	O
.	O


Since	O
opening	O
in	O
late	O
2006	O
,	O
Suvarnabhumi	AIRPORT
has	O
faced	O
more	O
than	O
the	O
usual	O
spate	O
of	O
start-up	O
stumbles	O
and	O
critical	O
press	O
.	O
Objections	O
—	O
focused	O
on	O
everything	O
from	O
circulation	O
,	O
seating	O
,	O
and	O
restrooms	O
to	O
cracked	O
runways	O
—	O
have	O
been	O
intensified	O
by	O
accusations	O
of	O
corrupt	O
construction	O
management	O
and	O
concession	O
leasing	O
.	O


Since	O
Suvarnabhumi	AIRPORT
represents	O
a	O
huge	O
public	O
and	O
private	O
investment	O
,	O
said	O
to	O
exceed	O
$	O
3	O
billion	O
,	O
including	O
aircraft-maintenance	O
facilities	O
,	O
parking	O
garages	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
hotel	O
(	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
the	O
sleek	O
new	O
highway	O
connecting	O
the	O
terminal	O
to	O
the	O
city	O
and	O
the	O
mass-transit	O
link	O
currently	O
under	O
construction	O
),	O
the	O
airport	O
management	O
is	O
trying	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
problems	O
.	O


Initial	O
glitches	O
aside	O
,	O
the	O
airport	O
will	O
clearly	O
remain	O
Bangkok	CITY
's	O
key	O
connection	O
to	O
the	O
world	O
.	O


But	O
the	O
engineers	O
who	O
made	O
it	O
all	O
possible	O
were	O
not	O
yet	O
involved	O
when	O
the	O
scheme	O
won	O
the	O
project	O
competition	O
.	O
Once	O
those	O
consultants	O
came	O
on	O
board	O
,	O
it	O
became	O
apparent	O
that	O
the	O
proposal	O
's	O
scale	O
demanded	O
exceptional	O
engineering	O
,	O
both	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
structure	O
itself	O
feasible	O
and	O
to	O
manage	O
the	O
energy	O
to	O
operate	O
it	O
.	O
The	O
architects	O
found	O
ideal	O
collaborators	O
in	O
two	O
Stuttgart	CITY
engineering	O
firms	O
:	O
Werner	ORGANIZATION
Sobek	ORGANIZATION
Ingenieure	ORGANIZATION
,	O
for	O
structural	O
issues	O
,	O
and	O
Transsolar	ORGANIZATION
Energietechnik	ORGANIZATION
,	O
for	O
climate	O
control	O
.	O

Subscribe	O
to	O
Architectural	ORGANIZATION
Record	ORGANIZATION
in	O
print	O
|	O
Buy	O
Back	O
Issues	O
|	O
Manage	O
your	O
subscription	O
|	O
Get	O
Architectural	O
Record	O
digitally	O
|	O
Sign	O
up	O
for	O
Free	O
Architectural	ORGANIZATION
Record	ORGANIZATION
newsletter	O


Reader	O
Comments	O
:	O


We	O
welcome	O
comments	O
from	O
all	O
points	O
of	O
view	O
.	O
Off-topic	O
or	O
abusive	O
comments	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
removed	O
at	O
the	O
editors	O
?	O
discretion	O
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


4	O
.	O
Airport	O
Transportation	O
Options	O


There	O
are	O
many	O
transportation	O
options	O
available	O
from	O
San	AIRPORT
Francisco	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
.	O
These	O
transportation	O
options	O
can	O
take	O
you	O
from	O
the	O
airport	O
to	O
the	O
City	CITY
of	CITY
San	CITY
Francisco	CITY
and	O
the	O
surrounding	O
areas	O
.	O
At	O
the	O
airport	O
there	O
are	O
the	O
transportation	O
options	O
of	O
BART	MISC
,	O
CalTrain	MISC
,	O
bus	O
services	O
,	O
shuttle	O
buses	O
,	O
limousine	O
services	O
,	O
and	O
taxis	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
a	O
train	O
that	O
circulates	O
the	O
airport	O
called	O
the	O
AirTrain	MISC
that	O
connects	O
the	O
terminals	O
,	O
the	O
car	O
parking	O
areas	O
,	O
car	O
rental	O
areas	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
airport	O
BART	MISC
station	O
.	O


The	O
BART	MISC
metro	O
train	O
is	O
the	O
least	O
expensive	O
way	O
to	O
travel	O
to	O
San	CITY
Francisco	CITY
and	O
to	O
other	O
destinations	O
in	O
the	O
Bay	LOCATION
Area	LOCATION
.	O
BART	MISC
tickets	O
are	O
available	O
at	O
the	O
BART	MISC
station	O
and	O
accept	O
both	O
cash	O
and	O
credit	O
cards	O
.	O
The	O
San	AIRPORT
Francisco	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
BART	MISC
runs	O
Monday	O
-	O
Friday	O
between	O
4	O
AM	O
and	O
midnight	O
,	O
on	O
Saturday	O
between	O
6	O
AM	O
and	O
midnight	O
,	O
and	O
Sunday	O
between	O
8	O
AM	O
and	O
midnight	O
.	O


Near	O
the	O
airport	O
there	O
is	O
the	O
San	LOCATION
Francisco	LOCATION
Millbrae	LOCATION
CalTrain	LOCATION
railway	LOCATION
station	LOCATION
.	O
To	O
get	O
to	O
the	O
station	O
form	O
the	O
airport	O
you	O
can	O
take	O
the	O
CalTrain	MISC
shuttle	O
bus	O
.	O
The	O
trains	O
make	O
several	O
stops	O
on	O
its	O
journey	O
at	O
train	O
stations	O
in	O
Palo	CITY
Alto	CITY
and	O
Stanford	CITY
.	O
This	O
railway	O
system	O
does	O
not	O
head	O
north	O
to	O
San	CITY
Francisco	CITY
.	O


San	AIRPORT
Francisco	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
has	O
San	MISC
Francisco	MISC
Airporter	MISC
buses	O
available	O
that	O
travel	O
to	O
San	CITY
Francisco	CITY
and	O
other	O
destinations	O
in	O
the	O
Bay	LOCATION
Area	LOCATION
.	O

These	O
buses	O
depart	O
from	O
outside	O
the	O
Baggage	O
Claim	O
area	O
and	O
depart	O
every	O
12-30	O
minutes	O
.	O
These	O
buses	O
are	O
in	O
operation	O
from	O
6	O
:	O
20	O
AM	O
to	O
midnight	O
every	O
day	O
.	O
Besides	O
the	O
BART	MISC
these	O
buses	O
are	O
the	O
cheapest	O
way	O
to	O
get	O
to	O
your	O
destination	O
in	O
the	O
Bay	O
Area	O
.	O
There	O
is	O
a	O
bus	O
stop	O
outside	O
of	O
Terminal	O
3	O
(	O
near	O
Courtyard	O
4	O
)	O
and	O
the	O
International	O
Terminal	O
(	O
near	O
Courtyard	O
A	O
).	O


There	O
are	O
many	O
taxis	O
available	O
at	O
San	AIRPORT
Francisco	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
.	O
The	O
taxis	O
are	O
outside	O
the	O
Baggage	O
Claim	O
area	O
of	O
Terminals	O
1	O
and	O
3	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
at	O
level	O
2	O
of	O
the	O
Arrivals	O
area	O
at	O
the	O
International	O
Terminal	O
.	O
You	O
should	O
use	O
the	O
official	O
SFO	AIRPORT
taxis	O
to	O
make	O
sure	O
you	O
are	O
safe	O
and	O
not	O
overcharged	O
.	O
The	O
taxis	O
begin	O
at	O
a	O
basic	O
fare	O
but	O
there	O
are	O
other	O
charges	O
for	O
driving	O
late	O
at	O
night	O
and	O
on	O
the	O
holidays	O
and	O
for	O
luggage	O
.	O
You	O
should	O
check	O
the	O
fare	O
to	O
your	O
destination	O
beforehand	O
so	O
there	O
are	O
no	O
misunderstandings	O
.	O
Some	O
taxis	O
at	O
the	O
airport	O
accept	O
credit	O
cards	O
.	O


There	O
are	O
hotel	O
shuttles	O
and	O
shared	O
vans	O
available	O
at	O
the	O
airport	O
.	O
The	O
shared	O
vans	O
offer	O
door-to-door	O
service	O
and	O
are	O
located	O
at	O
both	O
the	O
Departures	O
and	O
Ticketing	O
levels	O
of	O
the	O
terminals	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
many	O
courtesy	O
hotels	O
shuttles	O
available	O
and	O
you	O
should	O
check	O
with	O
your	O
accommodations	O
to	O
see	O
if	O
they	O
have	O
this	O
service	O
available	O
.	O


Need	O
Transportation	O
?	O
Call	O
800-984-4303	O


=-DOCSTART-	O


BUSINESS	O

A	O
Canadian	O
company	O
has	O
purchased	O
a	O
55,200-square-foot	O
industrial	O
facility	O
at	O
720	O
E.	O
Central	LOCATION
Florida	LOCATION
Parkway	LOCATION
,	O
near	O
Florida	LOCATION
's	LOCATION
Turnpike	LOCATION
in	O
south	O
Orange	LOCATION
County	LOCATION
,	O
not	O
far	O
from	O
Orlando	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
.	O
The	O
seller	O
was	O
the	O
Sherwin-Williams	ORGANIZATION
Co	ORGANIZATION
.	ORGANIZATION
and	O
the	O
buyer	O
was	O
Weatherstrong	ORGANIZATION
Building	ORGANIZATION
Products	ORGANIZATION
Ltd	ORGANIZATION
,	O
a	O
metal-fabrication	O
company	O
.	O
The	O
single-story	O
manufacturing	O
site	O
will	O
become	O
the	O
local	O
home	O
of	O
Weatherstrong	ORGANIZATION
Building	ORGANIZATION
Products	ORGANIZATION
,	O
which	O
is	O
based	O
in	O
Smiths	CITY
Falls	CITY
,	O
Ontario	LOCATION
.	O

Colliers	ORGANIZATION
International	ORGANIZATION
Central	ORGANIZATION
Florida	ORGANIZATION
's	O
Deborah	PERSON
Mickler	PERSON
and	O
Forrest	PERSON
Askew	PERSON
represented	O
the	O
owner	O
;	O
the	O
buyer	O
was	O
represented	O
by	O
Ray	PERSON
Romano	PERSON
of	O
CB	ORGANIZATION
Richard	ORGANIZATION
Ellis	ORGANIZATION
.	O

Sales	O
Greg	PERSON
Rebman	PERSON
of	O
Rebman	ORGANIZATION
Properties	ORGANIZATION
Inc	ORGANIZATION
.	ORGANIZATION
represented	O
the	O
seller	O
,	O
Industrias	ORGANIZATION
Vassallo	ORGANIZATION
Inc	ORGANIZATION
.	ORGANIZATION
,	O
in	O
the	O
sale	O
of	O
four	O
buildings	O
totaling	O
74,000	O
square	O
feet	O
on	O
24.8	O
acres	O
in	O
Lake	CITY
Wales	CITY
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Calatrava	O
station	O
.	O


Yesterday	O
,	O
Kim	PERSON
Day	PERSON
,	O
Denver	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
's	O
aviation	O
director	O
,	O
did	O
her	O
best	O
to	O
convince	O
city	O
council	O
members	O
that	O
her	O
team	O
is	O
being	O
sensible	O
in	O
its	O
approach	O
to	O
more	O
than	O
a	O
billion	O
dollars	O
in	O
construction	O
projects	O
at	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
tenth-busiest	O
airport	O
.	O
But	O
the	O
leaner	O
budget	O
Day	O
presented	O
raises	O
the	O
kind	O
of	O
questions	O
you	O
get	O
on	O
TV	O
shows	O
about	O
morbidly	O
obese	O
face-stuffers	O
trying	O
to	O
shed	O
their	O
bloat	O
:	O
Can	O
they	O
stick	O
to	O
it	O
?	O


As	O
detailed	O
in	O
my	O
2010	O
feature	O
"	O
DIA	O
Dreams	O
,"	O
Day	PERSON
believes	O
that	O
the	O
airport	O
has	O
to	O
invest	O
heavily	O
in	O
capital	O
improvements	O
--	O
and	O
a	O
far-flung	O
apparatus	O
of	O
consultants	O
,	O
conceptionalists	O
,	O
focus	O
groups	O
and	O
other	O
marketing	O
analysis	O
associated	O
with	O
those	O
moves	O
--	O
to	O
keep	O
competitive	O
in	O
the	O
rapidly	O
evolving	O
world	O
of	O
aviation	O
.	O
Since	O
most	O
of	O
DIA	AIRPORT
's	O
revenue	O
stream	O
comes	O
from	O
operations	O
rather	O
than	O
taxpayers	O
,	O
it	O
functions	O
far	O
more	O
independently	O
than	O
most	O
city	O
agencies	O
,	O
with	O
limited	O
oversight	O
on	O
how	O
money	O
gets	O
spent	O
.	O
But	O
that	O
hasn	O
't	O
discouraged	O
skepticism	O
about	O
everything	O
from	O
Day	PERSON
's	O
enthusiasm	O
for	O
pricey	O
Spanish	O
"	O
starchitect	O
"	O
Santiago	PERSON
Calatrava	PERSON
,	O
chosen	O
to	O
design	O
a	O
new	O
bridge	O
and	O
rail	O
station	O
to	O
the	O
south	O
of	O
the	O
existing	O
terminal	O
,	O
to	O
her	O
recent	O
ethics	O
reprimand	O
for	O
a	O
contractor-sponsored	O
trip	O
to	O
Greece	COUNTRY
.	O


But	O
see	O
this	O
account	O
of	O
the	O
latest	O
number-crunching	O
on	O
the	O
hotel-station	O
project	O
.	O
Day	PERSON
's	O
now	O
saying	O
her	O
team	O
can	O
trim	O
$	O
150	O
million	O
from	O
the	O
$	O
650	O
million	O
build	O
--	O
and	O
the	O
changes	O
will	O
be	O
hardly	O
noticeable	O
to	O
the	O
untrained	O
eye	O
.	O
But	O
if	O
DIA	AIRPORT
can	O
so	O
easily	O
get	O
by	O
with	O
a	O
hotel	O
and	O
station	O
complex	O
that	O
's	O
almost	O
a	O
third	O
smaller	O
than	O
what	O
was	O
originally	O
proposed	O
--	O
an	O
entire	O
floor	O
of	O
the	O
hotel	O
is	O
gone	O
--	O
it	O
makes	O
you	O
wonder	O
about	O
the	O
justifications	O
involved	O
in	O
the	O
original	O
design	O
.	O


Not	O
to	O
mention	O
the	O
$	O
33	O
million	O
that	O
's	O
already	O
been	O
spent	O
on	O
the	O
"	O
initial	O
concepting	O
"	O
work	O
on	O
the	O
project	O
.	O


As	O
for	O
the	O
bold	O
design	O
proposed	O
by	O
Calatrava	PERSON
--	O
hailed	O
by	O
our	O
own	O
Michael	PERSON
Paglia	PERSON
but	O
ripped	O
by	O
philistines	O
as	O
an	O
"	O
iconic	O
"	O
statement	O
that	O
the	O
city	O
can	O
't	O
afford	O
and	O
that	O
will	O
interfere	O
with	O
the	O
existing	O
iconography	O
--	O
the	O
airport	O
has	O
not	O
yet	O
identified	O
the	O
funds	O
to	O
pay	O
for	O
the	O
$	O
60	O
million	O
bridge	O
Calatrava	PERSON
wants	O
to	O
build	O
across	O
Peña	LOCATION
Boulevard	LOCATION
for	O
the	O
train	O
's	O
grand	O
entrance	O
.	O
RTD	MISC
is	O
prepared	O
to	O
do	O
a	O
$7.3	O
million	O
bridge	O
on	O
the	O
cheap	O
;	O
DIA	AIRPORT
can	O
kick	O
in	O
another	O
$	O
15	O
million	O
or	O
so	O
.	O
That	O
's	O
not	O
even	O
half	O
a	O
Calatrava	PERSON
.	O


Day	PERSON
has	O
insisted	O
that	O
Calatrava	PERSON
is	O
willing	O
to	O
make	O
changes	O
in	O
his	O
design	O
,	O
saying	O
,	O
"	O
Don	O
't	O
tell	O
me	O
what	O
to	O
cut	O
.	O
Tell	O
me	O
your	O
budget	O
."	O
But	O
whatever	O
the	O
budget	O
is	O
,	O
it	O
won	O
't	O
be	O
enough	O
.	O
Calatrava	PERSON
's	O
track	O
record	O
for	O
bringing	O
in	O
projects	O
that	O
cost	O
far	O
more	O
that	O
what	O
was	O
originally	O
envisioned	O
is	O
so	O
extensive	O
that	O
he	O
should	O
be	O
considered	O
a	O
serial	O
budget-buster	O
;	O
or	O
,	O
as	O
Robert	PERSON
Wilonsky	PERSON
once	O
put	O
it	O
in	O
the	O
Dallas	NEWSPAPER
Observer	NEWSPAPER
,	O
our	O
sister	O
paper	O
,	O
"	O
Calatrava	PERSON
is	O
Spanish	O
for	O
'	O
Over	O
Budget	O
'."	O


Calatrava	PERSON
has	O
said	O
that	O
's	O
a	O
bum	O
rap	O
,	O
that	O
every	O
expenditure	O
on	O
his	O
public	O
projects	O
has	O
to	O
be	O
authorized	O
by	O
the	O
officials	O
responsible	O
for	O
the	O
budget	O
.	O
So	O
the	O
issue	O
of	O
how	O
much	O
the	O
airport	O
is	O
prepared	O
to	O
spend	O
comes	O
back	O
,	O
again	O
,	O
to	O
Day	O
--	O
who	O
insists	O
she	O
wants	O
to	O
run	O
the	O
airport	O
like	O
a	O
business	O
.	O


But	O
will	O
that	O
business	O
resemble	O
Berkshire	ORGANIZATION
Hathaway	ORGANIZATION
--	O
or	O
Lehman	ORGANIZATION
Brothers	ORGANIZATION
?	O


More	O
from	O
our	O
Follow	O
That	O
Story	O
archive	O
:	O
"	O
Santiago	PERSON
Calatrava	PERSON
's	O
DIA	AIRPORT
project	O
:	O
A	O
bridge	O
too	O
far	O
?"	O


Tags	O
:	O


Denver	AIRPORT
International	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
,	O
Kim	PERSON
Day	PERSON
,	O
Michael	PERSON
Paglia	PERSON
,	O
Santiago	PERSON
Calatrava	PERSON


=-DOCSTART-	O


 	O

I	O
just	O
heard	O
this	O
song	O
for	O
the	O
very	O
1st	O
time	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
just	O
can	O
't	O
find	O
the	O
words	O
to	O
describe	O
how	O
good	O
it	O
is	O
.	O
One	O
of	O
the	O
best	O
songs	O
of	O
all	O
time	O
!	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Keith	PERSON
Richards	PERSON
'	O
Autobiography	O
:	O
Setting	MISC
Fire	MISC
to	MISC
Playboy	MISC
Mansion	MISC
,	MISC
Hallucinating	MISC
Cops	MISC
As	MISC
Dwarves	MISC
Etc	MISC
.	MISC
Etc	MISC
.	MISC


=-DOCSTART-	O



One	O
could	O
say	O
it	O
was	O
a	O
broken	O
record	O
that	O
helped	O
make	O
the	O
Bee	BAND
Gees	BAND
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
succesful	O
recording	O
groups	O
ever	O
.	O
One	O
day	O
in	O
the	O
mid-1950s	O
,	O
Barry	PERSON
Gibb	PERSON
and	O
his	O
twin	O
brothers	O
,	O
Maurice	PERSON
and	O
Robin	PERSON
,	O
saw	O
a	O
boy	O
lip-syncing	O
to	O
a	O
record	O
at	O
a	O
movie	O
theater	O
in	O
their	O
hometown	O
of	O
Manchester	CITY
,	O
England	COUNTRY
.	O
They	O
signed	O
on	O
to	O
do	O
the	O
same	O
and	O
were	O
record	O
to	O
the	O
theater	O
when	O
Maurice	PERSON
dropped	O
and	O
broke	O
the	O
record	O
to	O
which	O
they	O
were	O
going	O
to	O
lip-sync	O
.	O
The	O
brothers	O
decided	O
to	O
sing	O
live	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
audience	O
loved	O
it	O
.	O


The	O
Gibbs	MISC
came	O
from	O
a	O
musical	O
family	O
.	O
Their	O
mother	O
was	O
a	O
singer	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
father	O
,	O
Hugh	PERSON
,	O
was	O
a	O
drummer	O
and	O
big-band	O
leader	O
.	O
Soon	O
after	O
the	O
birth	O
of	O
brother	O
Andy	PERSON
,	O
the	O
family	O
moved	O
to	O
Queensland	LOCATION
,	O
Australia	COUNTRY
,	O
in	O
1958	O
.	O
They	O
continued	O
performing	O
as	O
The	BAND
Rattlesnakes	BAND
and	O
caught	O
the	O
attention	O
of	O
disc	O
jockey	O
Bill	PERSON
Gates	PERSON
and	O
promoter	O
Bill	PERSON
Goode	PERSON
.	O
Gates	PERSON
used	O
the	O
initials	O
he	O
shared	O
with	O
Goode	PERSON
to	O
rename	O
the	O
group	O
The	BAND
Bee	BAND
Gees	BAND
.	O


The	O
trio	O
had	O
performed	O
in	O
resorts	O
,	O
on	O
television	O
and	O
recorded	O
a	O
minor	O
hit	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
family	O
decided	O
to	O
return	O
to	O
England	COUNTRY
.	O
Before	O
leaving	O
,	O
Hugh	PERSON
Gibbs	PERSON
sent	O
a	O
demo	O
tape	O
to	O
Brian	PERSON
Epstein	PERSON
's	O
NEMS	ORGANIZATION
management	O
company	O
.	O
Back	O
in	O
England	COUNTRY
,	O
they	O
met	O
NEMS	ORGANIZATION
producer	O
Robert	PERSON
Stigwood	PERSON
,	O
who	O
signed	O
them	O
to	O
a	O
contract	O
,	O
added	O
Vince	PERSON
Melouney	PERSON
on	O
guitar	O
and	O
Colin	PERSON
Petersen	PERSON
on	O
drums	O
and	O
took	O
them	O
into	O
the	O
recording	O
studio	O
.	O
The	O
sessions	O
resulted	O
in	O
an	O
album	O
,	O
Bee	MISC
Gees	MISC
First	MISC
,	O
which	O
was	O
released	O
in	O
mid-1967	O
.	O


The	BAND
Bee	BAND
Gees	BAND
wrote	O
all	O
of	O
their	O
own	O
songs	O
and	O
sang	O
close	O
three-part	O
harmonies	O
.	O
Their	O
voices	O
blended	O
perfectly	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
way	O
that	O
The	BAND
Everly	BAND
Brothers	BAND
and	O
Beach	BAND
Boys	BAND
did	O
.	O
Barry	PERSON
sang	O
lead	O
on	O
many	O
songs	O
and	O
developed	O
a	O
falsetto	O
in	O
the	O
group	O
's	O
disco	O
years	O
.	O
Robin	PERSON
provided	O
the	O
lead	O
voice	O
in	O
their	O
early	O
recordings	O
,	O
and	O
Maurice	PERSON
did	O
the	O
high	O
and	O
low	O
harmonies	O
.	O


Promoter	PERSON
Stigwood	PERSON
decided	O
to	O
send	O
the	O
Bee	BAND
Gee	BAND
's	O
first	O
single	O
,	O
"	O
New	MISC
York	MISC
Mining	MISC
Disaster	MISC
1941	MISC
,"	O
to	O
radio	O
stations	O
with	O
a	O
white	O
label	O
that	O
contained	O
only	O
the	O
song	O
title	O
.	O
Many	O
DJs	O
assumed	O
it	O
was	O
from	O
the	O
Beatles	BAND
and	O
gave	O
it	O
heavy	O
airplay	O
.	O
"	O
Mining	MISC
Disaster	MISC
"	O
reached	O
the	O
top	O
20	O
in	O
both	O
the	O
UK	COUNTRY
and	O
the	O
US	COUNTRY
.	O
Their	O
follow-up	O
,	O
"	O
To	MISC
Love	MISC
Somebody	MISC
,"	O
also	O
climbed	O
to	O
the	O
top	O
20	O
.	O
A	O
third	O
single	O
,	O
"	O
Holiday	MISC
,"	O
peaked	O
at	O
#	O
16	O
in	O
the	O
US	COUNTRY
.	O


The	BAND
Bee	BAND
Gee	BAND
's	O
next	O
album	O
,	O
Horizontal	MISC
,	O
produced	O
yet	O
another	O
top	O
20	O
single	O
,	O
"	O
Massachusetts	MISC
."	O
The	O
hits	O
kept	O
on	O
coming	O
:	O
"	O
Words	MISC
,"	O
"	O
I	MISC
've	MISC
Gotta	MISC
Get	MISC
a	MISC
Message	MISC
to	MISC
You	MISC
"	O
and	O
"	O
I	MISC
Started	MISC
A	MISC
Joke	MISC
,"	O
which	O
reached	O
#	O
6	O
in	O
the	O
States	COUNTRY
.	O


Barry	PERSON
and	O
Robin	PERSON
Gibb	PERSON
are	O
presented	O
with	O
the	O
Order	MISC
of	MISC
the	MISC
British	MISC
Empire	MISC
medals	O
in	O
2006	O
.	O


By	O
1969	O
,	O
Robin	PERSON
Gibb	PERSON
and	O
guitarist	O
Vince	PERSON
Melouney	PERSON
left	O
the	O
Bee	BAND
Gees	BAND
.	O
The	O
brothers	O
reunited	O
late	O
in	O
1970	O
but	O
failed	O
to	O
recreate	O
their	O
earlier	O
successes	O
.	O
Five	O
years	O
later	O
,	O
they	O
were	O
recording	O
in	O
Miami	O
,	O
at	O
Eric	PERSON
Clapton	PERSON
's	O
suggestion	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
repertoire	O
turned	O
to	O
a	O
more	O
rhythmic	O
style	O
.	O
Thus	O
began	O
the	O
Bee	BAND
Gees	BAND
'	O
even	O
more	O
successful	O
second	O
incarnation	O
as	O
a	O
disco	O
group	O
.	O
But	O
the	O
band	O
faded	O
when	O
disco	O
died	O
in	O
the	O
early	O
1980s	O
and	O
released	O
only	O
a	O
few	O
minor	O
records	O
.	O


The	BAND
Bee	BAND
Gees	BAND
are	O
the	O
most	O
successful	O
trio	O
in	O
rock	O
and	O
roll	O
history	O
.	O
They	O
've	O
sold	O
more	O
than	O
110	O
million	O
records	O
worldwide	O
,	O
including	O
19	O
number-one	O
singles	O
over	O
a	O
career	O
that	O
has	O
spanned	O
5	O
decades	O
.	O
They	O
are	O
the	O
only	O
artists	O
in	O
history	O
to	O
have	O
five	O
singles	O
in	O
the	O
US	MISC
Top	MISC
10	MISC
at	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
six	O
consecutive	O
number	O
one	O
records	O
.	O


Where	O
Are	O
They	O
Now	O
?	O


Younger	O
brother	O
Andy	PERSON
Gibb	PERSON
,	O
who	O
'd	O
launched	O
a	O
solo	O
career	O
,	O
died	O
in	O
1988	O
at	O
age	O
30	O
.	O
Barry	PERSON
,	PERSON
Maurice	PERSON
and	O
Robin	PERSON
continued	O
as	O
the	O
Bee	BAND
Gees	BAND
through	O
the	O
90s	O
.	O
The	O
death	O
of	O
Maurice	PERSON
Gibb	PERSON
in	O
2003	O
retired	O
the	O
Bee	BAND
Gee	BAND
's	O
name	O
,	O
though	O
Barry	PERSON
and	O
Robin	PERSON
united	O
for	O
a	O
charity	O
concert	O
in	O
Miami	CITY
in	O
2006	O
and	O
say	O
they	O
're	O
open	O
to	O
the	O
idea	O
of	O
performing	O
again	O
together	O
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


R.E.	BAND
M	BAND
mark	O
the	O
point	O
when	O
post-punk	O
turned	O
into	O
alternative	O
rock	O
.	O
Throughout	O
the	O
'	O
80s	O
,	O
they	O
released	O
records	O
every	O
year	O
and	O
toured	O
constantly	O
,	O
along	O
the	O
way	O
,	O
they	O
inspired	O
countless	O
bands	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
legions	O
of	O
jangle	O
pop	O
groups	O
in	O
the	O
mid	O
-'	O
80s	O
to	O
scores	O
of	O
alternative	O
pop	O
groups	O
in	O
the	O
'	O
90s	O
.	O
By	O
the	O
late	O
'	O
80s	O
,	O
the	O
group	O
's	O
fan	O
base	O
had	O
grown	O
large	O
enough	O
to	O
guarantee	O
strong	O
sales	O
.	O
R.E.	BAND
M	BAND
slowly	O
became	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
most	O
popular	O
bands	O
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Talk	O
of	O
a	O
Rolling	BAND
Stones	BAND
tour	O
this	O
year	O
has	O
heated	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
wake	O
of	O
details	O
from	O
former	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
Chairman	O
Michael	PERSON
Cohl	PERSON
's	O
lawsuit	O
against	O
the	O
company	O
hitting	O
the	O
Internet	O
.	O
But	O
Billboard	O
sticks	O
by	O
its	O
assertion	O
that	O
if	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
were	O
to	O
tour	O
it	O
would	O
probably	O
not	O
be	O
until	O
next	O
year	O
,	O
or	O
late	O
this	O
year	O
at	O
the	O
earliest	O
--	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
themselves	O
basically	O
squelched	O
chatter	O
about	O
the	O
tour	O
via	O
a	O
statement	O
issued	O
today	O
,	O
without	O
ruling	O
it	O
out	O
completely	O
.	O


"	O
In	O
light	O
of	O
recent	O
reports	O
surrounding	O
the	O
'	MISC
Breach	MISC
of	MISC
Contract	MISC
'	MISC
Court	MISC
Case	MISC
in	O
America	LOCATION
between	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
Entertainment	ORGANIZATION
and	O
former	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
chairman	O
Michael	PERSON
Cohl	PERSON
,	O
The	BAND
Rolling	BAND
Stones	BAND
wish	O
to	O
clarify	O
their	O
position	O
regarding	O
representation	O
and	O
touring	O
,"	O
the	O
statement	O
reads	O
.	O
"	O
Following	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
2007	O
'	O
A	MISC
Bigger	MISC
Bang	MISC
'	O
world	O
tour	O
,	O
The	BAND
Rolling	BAND
Stones	BAND
became	O
free	O
from	O
any	O
contractual	O
arrangements	O
or	O
agreements	O
with	O
Michael	PERSON
Cohl	PERSON
.	O
He	O
is	O
neither	O
their	O
representative	O
nor	O
their	O
tour	O
promoter	O
.	O
Also	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
confirmed	O
today	O
they	O
have	O
no	O
firm	O
plans	O
to	O
tour	O
at	O
this	O
time	O
.	O

"	O
The	BAND
Rolling	BAND
Stones	BAND
have	O
recently	O
secured	O
a	O
worldwide	O
merchandizing	O
agreement	O
with	O
Bravado	ORGANIZATION
Inc	ORGANIZATION
.	ORGANIZATION
and	O
in	O
2008	O
signed	O
a	O
new	O
global	O
record	O
deal	O
with	O
Universal	ORGANIZATION
Music	ORGANIZATION
,"	O
it	O
adds	O
.	O

Any	O
squabbles	O
between	O
Cohl	PERSON
and	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
as	O
to	O
who	O
would	O
produce	O
such	O
a	O
tour	O
may	O
be	O
moot	O
,	O
as	O
ultimately	O
it	O
's	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
'	O
call	O
as	O
to	O
who	O
steers	O
the	O
ship	O
--	O
if	O
the	O
tour	O
sails	O
at	O
all	O
.	O
Cohl	PERSON
led	O
the	O
band	O
to	O
unprecedented	O
tour	O
grosses	O
with	O
his	O
dice-rolling	O
financing	O
,	O
creative	O
deals	O
and	O
market-value	O
ticket	O
prices	O
,	O
beginning	O
with	O
the	O
"	O
Steel	MISC
Wheels	MISC
"	O
trek	O
in	O
1989	O
.	O
But	O
all	O
of	O
Cohl	PERSON
's	O
tour	O
deals	O
with	O
the	O
Rolling	BAND
Stones	BAND
,	O
which	O
have	O
grossed	O
some	O
$	O
2	O
billion	O
in	O
ticket	O
sales	O
alone	O
since	O
1989	O
,	O
were	O
cut	O
on	O
a	O
tour-by-tour	O
basis	O
,	O
even	O
if	O
they	O
included	O
multiple	O
rights	O
such	O
as	O
DVDs	O
and	O
merchandising	O
that	O
extended	O
beyond	O
those	O
tours	O
'	O
conclusion	O
.	O
Cohl	PERSON
became	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
'	O
guy	O
because	O
he	O
and	O
his	O
team	O
got	O
the	O
job	O
done	O
on	O
all	O
levels	O
.	O

And	O
even	O
if	O
the	O
contract	O
surrounding	O
Cohl	PERSON
's	O
exit	O
with	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
apparently	O
gave	O
him	O
the	O
right	O
to	O
bid	O
on	O
a	O
Stones	BAND
tour	O
,	O
it	O
certainly	O
does	O
not	O
obligate	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
to	O
work	O
with	O
him	O
.	O

Cohl	PERSON
worked	O
with	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
promoters	O
in	O
various	O
markets	O
on	O
some	O
of	O
his	O
tours	O
with	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
,	O
but	O
before	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
existed	O
he	O
was	O
able	O
to	O
secure	O
financing	O
from	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
sources	O
that	O
bankrolled	O
the	O
massive	O
startup	O
costs	O
a	O
Stones	BAND
tour	O
requires	O
.	O
So	O
he	O
could	O
likely	O
get	O
the	O
job	O
done	O
without	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
,	O
and	O
indeed	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
could	O
get	O
the	O
job	O
done	O
without	O
Cohl	PERSON
and	O
perhaps	O
emerge	O
as	O
the	O
favorite	O
.	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
has	O
an	O
ace	O
in	O
the	O
hole	O
in	O
dealing	O
with	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
,	O
as	O
LN	ORGANIZATION
Global	ORGANIZATION
Touring	ORGANIZATION
Chairman	O
Arthur	PERSON
Fogel	PERSON
was	O
a	O
key	O
executive	O
under	O
Cohl	PERSON
at	O
the	O
latter	O
's	O
former	O
companies	O
CPI	ORGANIZATION
and	O
TNA	ORGANIZATION
before	O
they	O
became	O
part	O
of	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
.	O

Fogel	PERSON
has	O
in	O
fact	O
become	O
the	O
leading	O
mega-tour	O
producer	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
having	O
steered	O
with	O
his	O
Toronto	CITY
-	O
based	O
team	O
four	O
of	O
the	O
five	O
highest-grossing	O
tours	O
of	O
all	O
time	O
,	O
including	O
U2	BAND
's	O
ongoing	O
"	O
360	MISC
"	O
tour	O
.	O
That	O
tour	O
will	O
surpass	O
'	O
A	MISC
Bigger	MISC
Bang	MISC
'	O
tour	O
in	O
April	O
to	O
become	O
the	O
highest-grossing	O
tour	O
in	O
history	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
Billboard	NEWSPAPER
Boxscore	NEWSPAPER
.	O
By	O
the	O
time	O
"	O
360	MISC
"	O
wraps	O
July	O
30	O
at	O
the	O
Magnetic	LOCATION
Hill	LOCATION
Music	LOCATION
Festival	LOCATION
in	O
Moncton	CITY
,	O
New	LOCATION
Brunswick	LOCATION
,	O
the	O
gross	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
staggering	O
$	O
700	O
million	O
.	O

Those	O
types	O
of	O
numbers	O
surely	O
will	O
catch	O
the	O
eyes	O
of	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
'	O
Mick	PERSON
Jagger	PERSON
and	O
Keith	PERSON
Richards	PERSON
,	O
who	O
,	O
by	O
the	O
way	O
,	O
tend	O
to	O
at	O
least	O
take	O
a	O
stab	O
at	O
new	O
material	O
before	O
launching	O
a	O
tour	O
,	O
and	O
sources	O
say	O
no	O
band	O
meeting	O
has	O
been	O
called	O
as	O
of	O
yet	O
.	O

The	O
list	O
of	O
promoters	O
that	O
could	O
take	O
on	O
a	O
tour	O
of	O
this	O
magnitude	O
is	O
a	O
short	O
one	O
,	O
but	O
longer	O
than	O
it	O
was	O
even	O
a	O
few	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O
Sources	O
say	O
Cohl	PERSON
,	O
Live	ORGANIZATION
Nation	ORGANIZATION
,	O
Paul	PERSON
Dainty	PERSON
,	O
and	O
AEG	ORGANIZATION
Live	ORGANIZATION
would	O
be	O
in	O
the	O
running	O
for	O
the	O
next	O
Stones	BAND
tour	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
seems	O
all	O
these	O
names	O
surface	O
in	O
hopes	O
that	O
the	O
band	O
will	O
tour	O
,	O
not	O
because	O
the	O
band	O
is	O
soliciting	O
bids	O
.	O
Fogel	PERSON
has	O
his	O
recent	O
track	O
record	O
and	O
strong	O
history	O
with	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
,	O
and	O
though	O
today	O
's	O
statement	O
does	O
not	O
bode	O
well	O
,	O
Cohl	PERSON
should	O
never	O
be	O
counted	O
out	O
.	O

Even	O
if	O
Cohl	PERSON
is	O
completely	O
immersed	O
in	O
the	O
beast	O
that	O
is	O
"	O
Spiderman	MISC
:	MISC
Turn	MISC
Off	MISC
the	MISC
Dark	MISC
,"	O
he	O
tells	O
Billboard	NEWSPAPER
that	O
if	O
the	O
Stones	BAND
came	O
calling	O
,	O
"	O
I	O
always	O
have	O
time	O
for	O
the	O
Rolling	BAND
Stones	BAND
."	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Tweet	O


Share	O


When	O
I	O
first	O
started	O
birding	O
long	O
,	O
long	O
ago	O
(	O
how	O
long	O
?	O
pre-computer	O
,	O
but	O
post	O
the	O
printed	O
word	O
thankfully	O
)	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
birds	O
that	O
got	O
me	O
firmly	O
and	O
eternally	O
hooked	O
was	O
a	O
species	O
that	O
we	O
here	O
in	O
the	O
UK	COUNTRY
know	O
as	O
"	O
the	O
robin	O
".	O
A	O
small	O
,	O
rotund	O
,	O
fiery	O
bundle	O
of	O
aggression	O
and	O
sweet	O
song	O
,	O
the	O
European	MISC
Robin	MISC
Erithacus	MISC
rubecula	MISC
is	O
a	O
familiar	O
and	O
much-loved	O
species	O
across	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
–	O
so	O
well-known	O
and	O
well-regarded	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
chosen	O
as	O
Britain	MISC
's	MISC
National	MISC
Bird	MISC
in	O
a	O
public	O
ballot	O
in	O
1960	O
,	O
was	O
overwhelmingly	O
voted	O
favourite	O
garden	O
bird	O
in	O
an	O
online	O
poll	O
run	O
by	O
the	O
The	ORGANIZATION
Royal	ORGANIZATION
Society	ORGANIZATION
for	ORGANIZATION
the	ORGANIZATION
Protection	ORGANIZATION
of	ORGANIZATION
Birds	ORGANIZATION
(	O
RSPB	ORGANIZATION
)	O
in	O
2004	O
,	O
and	O
also	O
won	O
a	O
Gold	MISC
Medal	MISC
Award	MISC
after	O
being	O
voted	O
Scotland	COUNTRY
's	O
favourite	O
bird	O
in	O
the	O
RSPB	MISC
Scotland	MISC
Centenary	MISC
Awards	MISC
.	O
On	O
top	O
of	O
that	O
,	O
let	O
's	O
not	O
forget	O
,	O
its	O
name	O
(	O
which	O
apparently	O
means	O
"	O
famed	O
;	O
bright	O
;	O
shining	O
")	O
has	O
been	O
carried	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
by	O
European	O
emmigres	O
,	O
who	O
named	O
almost	O
any	O
unrelated	O
red-breasted	O
bird	O
they	O
came	O
across	O
"	O
Robin	MISC
"	O
in	O
countries	O
from	O
the	O
US	COUNTRY
(	O
yes	O
,	O
I	O
'm	O
talking	O
about	O
the	O
American	MISC
Robin	MISC
here	O
)	O
to	O
South	COUNTRY
Africa	COUNTRY
and	O
across	O
to	O
Asia	LOCATION
!	O


The	O
Real	O
red	O
,	O
red	O
robin	O
–	O
European	MISC
Robin	MISC
Erithacus	MISC
rubecula	MISC


Close	O
,	O
but	O
no	O
prize	O
:	O
American	MISC
Robin	MISC
Turdus	MISC
migratorius	MISC
(	O
above	O
),	O
and	O
Cape	MISC
Robin	MISC
Cossypha	MISC
caffra	MISC


European	O
birders	O
I	O
know	O
always	O
seem	O
a	O
little	O
bewildered	O
that	O
us	O
Brits	O
are	O
so	O
enamoured	O
of	O
Robins	O
.	O
Though	O
they	O
range	O
across	O
Europe	LOCATION
(	O
including	O
the	O
Mediterranean	O
islands	O
)	O
to	O
North	LOCATION
Africa	LOCATION
and	O
east	O
to	O
West	LOCATION
Siberia	LOCATION
and	O
Iran	COUNTRY
,	O
in	O
most	O
areas	O
they	O
are	O
shy	O
birds	O
that	O
are	O
seen	O
no	O
more	O
commonly	O
than	O
any	O
other	O
small	O
,	O
brown	O
skulking	O
bird	O
and	O
are	O
little	O
more	O
than	O
contributors	O
to	O
the	O
background	O
of	O
songs	O
emerging	O
from	O
forests	O
and	O
dense	O
thickets	O
.	O
In	O
Britain	COUNTRY
,	O
though	O
,	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
have	O
apparently	O
found	O
ther	O
courage	O
and	O
are	O
commonly	O
seen	O
in	O
gardens	O
–	O
and	O
every	O
keen	O
gardener	O
you	O
care	O
to	O
talk	O
to	O
(	O
and	O
if	O
Britain	COUNTRY
's	O
anything	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
nation	O
of	O
gardeners	O
)	O
seems	O
to	O
have	O
their	O
own	O
tale	O
to	O
tell	O
of	O
a	O
Robin	MISC
hopping	O
onto	O
a	O
garden	O
spade	O
and	O
fixing	O
its	O
steady	O
gaze	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
below	O
.	O
The	O
reason	O
appears	O
to	O
be	O
that	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
have	O
long	O
followed	O
foraging	O
animals	O
like	O
Wild	O
Boars	O
as	O
they	O
turn	O
over	O
the	O
earth	O
looking	O
for	O
roots	O
,	O
nuts	O
,	O
and	O
fruit	O
etc	O
–	O
flitting	O
down	O
to	O
snatch	O
disturbed	O
insects	O
or	O
earthworms	O
in	O
their	O
wake	O
:	O
gardeners	O
,	O
with	O
their	O
forks	O
and	O
spades	O
,	O
are	O
in	O
effect	O
nothing	O
more	O
than	O
two-legged	O
wild	O
boars	O
in	O
old	O
sweaters	O
turning	O
over	O
the	O
soil	O
.	O
It	O
's	O
not	O
quite	O
as	O
romantic	O
as	O
"	O
humans	O
and	O
wild	O
birds	O
forge	O
extraordinary	O
close	O
bonds	O
"	O
–	O
but	O
it	O
's	O
probably	O
more	O
accurate	O
…	O


Talking	O
of	O
‘	O
accurate	O
'	O
much	O
of	O
what	O
we	O
know	O
about	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
is	O
down	O
to	O
a	O
near-legendary	O
ornithologist	O
called	O
David	PERSON
Lack	PERSON
,	O
a	O
renowned	O
observer	O
of	O
bird	O
behaviour	O
,	O
who	O
in	O
the	O
1940s	O
wrote	O
"	O
The	MISC
Life	MISC
of	MISC
the	MISC
Robin	MISC
"	O
and	O
discovered	O
just	O
how	O
enraged	O
both	O
males	O
and	O
females	O
birds	O
became	O
when	O
confronted	O
with	O
another	O
Robin	MISC
's	O
red-breast	O
feathers	O
:	O
"	O
An	O
exceptionally	O
violent	O
hen	O
Robin	MISC
attacked	O
the	O
specimen	O
so	O
strongly	O
that	O
she	O
removed	O
its	O
head	O
.	O
For	O
a	O
moment	O
the	O
bird	O
seemed	O
rather	O
startled	O
,	O
but	O
then	O
continued	O
to	O
attack	O
the	O
headless	O
specimen	O
as	O
violently	O
as	O
before	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
seemed	O
as	O
though	O
it	O
might	O
have	O
demolished	O
it	O
completely	O
if	O
I	O
had	O
not	O
interrupted	O
proceedings	O
…."	O
Lack	O
went	O
on	O
to	O
experiment	O
and	O
discovered	O
that	O
"	O
a	O
headless	O
,	O
wingless	O
,	O
tailless	O
,	O
legless	O
and	O
bodiless	O
bundle	O
of	O
red	O
feathers	O
appears	O
as	O
a	O
rival	O
to	O
be	O
attacked	O
…	O
Even	O
the	O
empty	O
air	O
can	O
contain	O
a	O
rival	O
to	O
be	O
destroyed	O
.	O
The	O
world	O
of	O
the	O
Robin	MISC
is	O
so	O
strange	O
and	O
remote	O
from	O
our	O
experience	O
that	O
into	O
it	O
we	O
can	O
scarcely	O
penetrate	O
,	O
except	O
to	O
see	O
dimly	O
how	O
different	O
it	O
must	O
be	O
from	O
our	O
own	O
."	O

A	O
warning	O
to	O
gardeners	O
everywhere	O
to	O
stick	O
to	O
neutral	O
colours	O
when	O
they	O
venture	O
into	O
the	O
flower-beds	O
with	O
their	O
hoes	O
!	O


Robin	MISC
s	O
were	O
very	O
well-known	O
to	O
the	O
rural	O
folk	O
of	O
Britain	COUNTRY
(	O
they	O
're	O
found	O
all	O
year	O
round	O
here	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
vivid	O
red	O
breast	O
must	O
have	O
made	O
them	O
quite	O
visible	O
in	O
the	O
depths	O
of	O
a	O
snowy	O
winter	O
)	O
and	O
a	O
huge	O
and	O
wonderful	O
amount	O
of	O
folklore	O
has	O
grown	O
up	O
around	O
them	O
.	O
A	O
number	O
of	O
stories	O
seek	O
to	O
explain	O
the	O
origin	O
of	O
the	O
red	O
breast	O
,	O
one	O
tale	O
saying	O
that	O
as	O
Jesus	PERSON
was	O
on	O
his	O
way	O
to	O
be	O
crucified	O
a	O
Robin	MISC
removed	O
a	O
thorn	O
from	O
the	O
crown	O
that	O
was	O
piercing	O
his	O
forehead	O
,	O
pricking	O
its	O
breast	O
and	O
staining	O
its	O
feathers	O
with	O
blood	O
.	O
Another	O
story	O
suggests	O
that	O
the	O
Robin	MISC
's	O
breast	O
was	O
singed	O
while	O
fanning	O
the	O
fire	O
to	O
warm	O
baby	O
Jesus	PERSON
(	O
or	O
alternatively	O
was	O
singed	O
while	O
trying	O
to	O
cool	O
sinners	O
in	O
Hell	O
by	O
fanning	O
them	O
).	O


Another	O
belief	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
position	O
of	O
a	O
Robin	MISC
when	O
singing	O
could	O
be	O
used	O
to	O
forecast	O
the	O
weather	O
:	O
if	O
it	O
sang	O
on	O
top	O
of	O
a	O
bush	O
the	O
weather	O
would	O
be	O
warm	O
,	O
while	O
if	O
it	O
sang	O
from	O
within	O
the	O
branches	O
then	O
rain	O
was	O
on	O
the	O
way	O
.	O
One	O
strange	O
belief	O
about	O
the	O
Robin	MISC
was	O
that	O
if	O
it	O
found	O
a	O
dead	O
body	O
it	O
would	O
cover	O
it	O
with	O
leaves	O
or	O
moss	O
(	O
it	O
's	O
just	O
a	O
thought	O
,	O
but	O
perhaps	O
this	O
arose	O
because	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
would	O
be	O
attracted	O
to	O
the	O
flies	O
around	O
hidden	O
corpses	O
and	O
turn	O
over	O
the	O
leaves	O
used	O
to	O
hide	O
the	O
body	O
to	O
get	O
to	O
them	O
?).	O
It	O
was	O
also	O
thought	O
to	O
be	O
extremely	O
unlucky	O
to	O
kill	O
the	O
bird	O
.	O
According	O
to	O
one	O
superstition	O
,	O
if	O
you	O
killed	O
a	O
Robin	MISC
your	O
hands	O
would	O
not	O
stop	O
shaking	O
,	O
while	O
anyone	O
who	O
broke	O
its	O
eggs	O
would	O
have	O
something	O
valuable	O
of	O
their	O
own	O
broken	O
.	O
Great	O
stuff	O
,	O
and	O
as	O
an	O
aside	O
it	O
's	O
quite	O
sad	O
to	O
reflect	O
that	O
in	O
our	O
far	O
more	O
urban	O
and	O
mechanised	O
environment	O
the	O
days	O
when	O
such	O
folklore	O
might	O
arise	O
are	O
probably	O
long	O
gone	O
…	O


That	O
's	O
not	O
to	O
say	O
that	O
people	O
will	O
stop	O
admiring	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
of	O
course	O
.	O
Most	O
people	O
with	O
any	O
interest	O
in	O
birds	O
at	O
all	O
–	O
and	O
thanks	O
to	O
programme	O
's	O
like	O
the	O
BBC	ORGANIZATION
's	O
superb	O
"	O
Springwatch	MISC
"	O
that	O
number	O
does	O
seem	O
to	O
be	O
growing	O
–	O
know	O
and	O
love	O
Robin	MISC
s.	O
Friendly	O
,	O
familiar	O
,	O
tuneful	O
,	O
and	O
used	O
to	O
decorate	O
Christmas	MISC
cards	O
by	O
the	O
forest	O
load	O
(	O
in	O
1999	O
a	O
pensioner	O
in	O
Kent	CITY
,	O
UK	COUNTRY
held	O
the	O
Guinness	MISC
Book	MISC
of	MISC
Records	MISC
record	O
for	O
the	O
largest	O
Robin	MISC
Christmas	MISC
card	O
Collection	O
:	O
she	O
had	O
a	O
mind-blowing	O
10,677	O
different	O
cards	O
[	O
and	O
the	O
sort	O
of	O
record	O
that	O
re-enforces	O
my	O
opinion	O
that	O
the	O
GB	MISC
of	MISC
R	MISC
ran	O
out	O
of	O
proper	O
record-holders	O
aeons	O
ago	O
])	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
Robin	MISC
does	O
seem	O
to	O
be	O
reasonably	O
secure	O
.	O
Estimates	O
of	O
the	O
population	O
in	O
the	O
UK	COUNTRY
suggest	O
that	O
they	O
're	O
one	O
of	O
just	O
a	O
handful	O
of	O
species	O
to	O
have	O
increased	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
,	O
and	O
unless	O
they	O
start	O
viciously	O
attacking	O
allotment-owners	O
and	O
pensioners	O
putting	O
out	O
plants	O
in	O
their	O
backyards	O
that	O
shouldn	O
't	O
change	O
.	O
I	O
hope	O
not	O
anyway	O
.	O
Iit	O
's	O
a	O
treat	O
to	O
wake	O
up	O
to	O
a	O
Robin	MISC
's	O
rich	O
song	O
in	O
the	O
suburbs	O
where	O
I	O
live	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
dare	O
say	O
that	O
sentiment	O
would	O
be	O
echoed	O
right	O
across	O
the	O
country	O
,	O
though	O
probably	O
not	O
as	O
movingly	O
as	O
the	O
lines	O
from	O
William	PERSON
Blake	PERSON
's	O
furious	O
poem	O
"	O
Auguries	MISC
of	MISC
Innocence	MISC
":	O


=-DOCSTART-	O


The	O
Robin	MISC
is	O
a	O
small	O
bird	O
,	O
originally	O
found	O
in	O
only	O
Europe	LOCATION
and	O
Asia	LOCATION
.	O
The	O
Robin	MISC
today	O
can	O
be	O
found	O
across	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
parts	O
of	O
Africa	LOCATION
,	O
North	LOCATION
America	LOCATION
and	O
New	COUNTRY
Zealand	COUNTRY
but	O
all	O
of	O
these	O
Robin	MISC
species	O
are	O
believed	O
to	O
be	O
subspecies	O
of	O
the	O
European	O
Robin	MISC
.	O


The	O
European	MISC
Robin	MISC
has	O
a	O
bright	O
orange	O
/	O
red	O
chest	O
and	O
is	O
the	O
most	O
distinctive	O
bird	O
of	O
the	O
Robin	MISC
family	O
.	O
Despite	O
the	O
bright	O
chest	O
of	O
the	O
European	MISC
Robin	MISC
,	O
other	O
species	O
of	O
female	O
Robin	MISC
are	O
fairly	O
plain	O
and	O
brown	O
in	O
colour	O
.	O
The	O
female	O
Robin	MISC
is	O
very	O
similar	O
in	O
both	O
size	O
and	O
appearance	O
to	O
the	O
nightingale	O
and	O
the	O
two	O
are	O
commonly	O
confused	O
.	O


The	O
New	MISC
Zealand	MISC
Robin	MISC
and	O
the	O
North	MISC
American	MISC
Robin	MISC
look	O
fairly	O
similar	O
to	O
the	O
female	O
European	MISC
Robin	MISC
,	O
and	O
all	O
these	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
are	O
brown	O
in	O
colour	O
.	O
The	O
North	MISC
American	MISC
Robin	MISC
is	O
not	O
to	O
be	O
confused	O
with	O
the	O
American	MISC
Robin	MISC
which	O
is	O
actually	O
a	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
thrush	O
family	O
rather	O
than	O
being	O
a	O
species	O
of	O
Robin	MISC
.	O
The	O
American	MISC
Robin	MISC
is	O
named	O
after	O
the	O
European	MISC
Robin	MISC
due	O
to	O
it	O
's	O
brightly	O
coloured	O
orange	O
chest	O
.	O


There	O
are	O
thought	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
than	O
45	O
different	O
species	O
of	O
Robin	MISC
found	O
on	O
the	O
Australian	O
continent	O
including	O
Australia	COUNTRY
,	O
Papua	COUNTRY
New	COUNTRY
Guinea	COUNTRY
and	O
numerous	O
other	O
islands	O
in	O
the	O
South	LOCATION
Pacific	LOCATION
.	O
These	O
birds	O
are	O
known	O
as	O
Australasian	MISC
Robin	MISC
s	O
and	O
are	O
all	O
small	O
sized	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
stocky	O
build	O
and	O
rounded	O
head	O
.	O


Robin	MISC
s	O
are	O
omnivorous	O
birds	O
feeding	O
on	O
a	O
mixture	O
of	O
both	O
plants	O
and	O
animals	O
.	O
The	O
Robin	MISC
primarily	O
eats	O
insects	O
and	O
worms	O
,	O
which	O
it	O
does	O
so	O
by	O
swooping	O
down	O
on	O
them	O
from	O
the	O
perch	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
watching	O
it	O
's	O
prey	O
from	O
.	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
sit	O
on	O
tree	O
branches	O
and	O
in	O
hedgerows	O
watching	O
their	O
prey	O
moving	O
around	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
before	O
they	O
suddenly	O
fly	O
down	O
to	O
eat	O
.	O

Robin	MISC
s	O
also	O
eat	O
fruits	O
,	O
seeds	O
and	O
berries	O
when	O
they	O
are	O
in	O
abundance	O
during	O
the	O
warmer	O
months	O
of	O
the	O
year	O
.	O


Generally	O
,	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
do	O
not	O
migrate	O
(	O
particularly	O
those	O
found	O
in	O
the	O
UK	COUNTRY
).	O
It	O
is	O
known	O
however	O
,	O
that	O
those	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
that	O
inhabit	O
areas	O
within	O
the	O
Arctic	LOCATION
circle	LOCATION
,	O
such	O
as	O
Scandinavia	LOCATION
,	O
do	O
migrate	O
south	O
to	O
the	O
warmer	O
climates	O
of	O
the	O
United	COUNTRY
Kingdom	COUNTRY
and	O
parts	O
of	O
Europe	O
to	O
escape	O
the	O
bitterly	O
cold	O
winters	O
.	O


Robin	MISC
s	O
mate	O
in	O
the	O
late	O
winter	O
to	O
early	O
spring	O
.	O
Female	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
build	O
a	O
nest	O
not	O
far	O
from	O
the	O
ground	O
generally	O
in	O
trees	O
or	O
dense	O
hedgerows	O
.	O
It	O
is	O
not	O
uncommon	O
however	O
to	O
find	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
nesting	O
is	O
slightly	O
strange	O
places	O
such	O
as	O
holes	O
in	O
stone	O
walls	O
and	O
even	O
in	O
letter	O
boxes	O
.	O
The	O
female	O
Robin	MISC
lays	O
4	O
or	O
5	O
white	O
coloured	O
eggs	O
that	O
hatch	O
after	O
an	O
incubation	O
period	O
of	O
just	O
under	O
2	O
weeks	O
.	O
Although	O
the	O
male	O
Robin	MISC
does	O
not	O
help	O
to	O
incubate	O
the	O
eggs	O
,	O
male	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
are	O
known	O
to	O
bring	O
the	O
female	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
food	O
whilst	O
they	O
are	O
sitting	O
on	O
their	O
nest	O
.	O


When	O
the	O
Robin	MISC
chicks	O
hatch	O
they	O
are	O
a	O
brown	O
colour	O
and	O
do	O
not	O
develop	O
the	O
bright	O
orange	O
chest	O
of	O
their	O
parents	O
until	O
they	O
are	O
older	O
.	O
The	O
female	O
Robin	MISC
regularly	O
leaves	O
her	O
chicks	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
help	O
the	O
male	O
Robin	MISC
collect	O
food	O
.	O
Both	O
parents	O
are	O
known	O
to	O
feed	O
their	O
Robin	MISC
chicks	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
month	O
,	O
although	O
Robin	MISC
families	O
are	O
known	O
to	O
abandon	O
their	O
original	O
nest	O
after	O
two	O
weeks	O
of	O
the	O
chicks	O
hatching	O
and	O
find	O
somewhere	O
new	O
where	O
food	O
is	O
in	O
greater	O
supply	O
.	O


Due	O
to	O
their	O
small	O
size	O
,	O
Robin	MISC
s	O
have	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
natural	O
predators	O
in	O
the	O
wild	O
including	O
cats	O
,	O
dogs	O
,	O
foxes	O
,	O
raccoons	O
and	O
even	O
larger	O
birds	O
.	O
Other	O
animals	O
such	O
as	O
rats	O
and	O
snakes	O
are	O
known	O
to	O
eat	O
the	O
eggs	O
of	O
the	O
Robin	MISC
if	O
for	O
some	O
reason	O
the	O
female	O
Robin	MISC
cannot	O
protect	O
them	O
.	O


=-DOCSTART-	O



The	O
Noble	CAR
M15	CAR
is	O
a	O
new	O
sports	O
car	O
designed	O
and	O
developed	O
by	O
Noble	ORGANIZATION
Automotive	ORGANIZATION
,	O
a	O
high-performance	O
sports	O
car	O
manufacturer	O
based	O
in	O
Leicestershire	CITY
.	O


Production	O
of	O
the	O
M15	CAR
began	O
early	O
in	O
2006	O
.	O
The	O
Noble	CAR
M15	CAR
is	O
intended	O
to	O
appeal	O
to	O
a	O
far	O
broader	O
market	O
than	O
the	O
M12-GTO3R	CAR
or	O
the	O
M400	CAR
and	O
compete	O
directly	O
with	O
the	O
Porsche	CAR
911	CAR
Turbo	CAR
/	CAR
GT-3	CAR
and	O
Ferrari	CAR
F430	CAR
.	O
As	O
a	O
result	O
the	O
Noble	CAR
M15	CAR
has	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
features	O
not	O
previously	O
found	O
on	O
Noble	ORGANIZATION
s	O
such	O
as	O
satellite	O
navigation	O
,	O
traction	O
control	O
,	O
electric	O
windows	O
and	O
ABS	O
.	O


Noble	ORGANIZATION
founder	O
Lee	PERSON
Noble	PERSON
has	O
been	O
quoted	O
in	O
indicating	O
"	O
the	O
M12	CAR
is	O
a	O
great	O
car	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
's	O
very	O
focused	O
and	O
[	O
he	O
]	O
wanted	O
to	O
produce	O
a	O
supercar	O
people	O
could	O
use	O
everyday	O
...	O
It	O
was	O
time	O
for	O
Noble	ORGANIZATION
to	O
take	O
a	O
big	O
step	O
up	O
in	O
terms	O
of	O
refinement	O
,	O
practicality	O
and	O
style	O
."	O
Despite	O
increased	O
comfort	O
and	O
usability	O
compared	O
to	O
previous	O
Noble	ORGANIZATION
cars	O
,	O
Lee	PERSON
Noble	PERSON
has	O
also	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
M15	CAR
is	O
significantly	O
quicker	O
than	O
the	O
M400	CAR
around	O
a	O
race	O
track	O
. 	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Bunkie	PERSON
Knudsen	PERSON
and	O
Larry	PERSON
Shinoda	PERSON
's	O
"	O
killer	O
"	O
fastback	O
was	O
ready	O
by	O
March	O
and	O
out	O
to	O
even	O
the	O
score	O
with	O
anything	O
Mustang	CAR
's	O
pony	O
car	O
competition	O
could	O
offer	O
,	O
at	O
least	O
on	O
the	O
street	O
.	O
They	O
were	O
going	O
to	O
call	O
it	O
"	O
Trans-Am	CAR
"	O
until	O
Pontiac	ORGANIZATION
grabbed	O
the	O
name	O
for	O
its	O
hottest	O
'	CAR
69	CAR
Firebird	CAR
,	O
so	O
they	O
settled	O
on	O
Boss	CAR
302	CAR
.	O
Trans-Am	CAR
rules	O
required	O
1000	O
copies	O
be	O
built	O
for	O
sale	O
to	O
qualify	O
as	O
"	O
production	O
,"	O
but	O
Ford	ORGANIZATION
ended	O
up	O
turning	O
out	O
1934	O
of	O
the	O
'	O
69s	O
.	O
Despite	O
even	O
that	O
low	O
number	O
,	O
the	O
Boss	CAR
brought	O
people	O
into	O
Ford	ORGANIZATION
showrooms	O
like	O
no	O
Mustang	CAR
since	O
the	O
original	O
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


After	O
almost	O
two	O
weeks	O
of	O
tectonic	O
protests	O
in	O
Cairo	CITY
that	O
have	O
rocked	O
the	O
Arab	O
world	O
,	O
Christiane	PERSON
Amanpour	PERSON
sat	O
down	O
with	O
five	O
top	O
journalists	O
to	O
look	O
at	O
a	O
key	O
question	O
:	O
what	O
happens	O
next	O
?	O


More	O
Video	O


Veteran	O
Egyptian	O
journalist	O
Nadia	PERSON
abou	PERSON
el-Magd	PERSON
said	O
it	O
comes	O
down	O
to	O
the	O
protesters	O
.	O
"	O
They	O
that	O
made	O
revolution	O
and	O
they	O
are	O
in	O
the	O
position	O
to	O
impose	O
their	O
conditions	O
,"	O

said	O
el-Magd	PERSON
,	O
who	O
works	O
for	O
the	O
newspaper	O
Al-Ahram	NEWSPAPER
and	O
The	NEWSPAPER
Associated	NEWSPAPER
Press	NEWSPAPER
.	O
"	O
They	O
don	O
't	O
see	O
that	O
...	O
anybody	O
else	O
is	O
in	O
a	O
position	O
to	O
impose	O
their	O
conditions	O
on	O
them	O
."	O


Egyptian	O
journalist	O
Lamia	PERSON
Radi	PERSON
said	O
the	O
protestors	O
"	O
will	O
try	O
to	O
stay	O
as	O
long	O
as	O
they	O
can	O
,"	O
but	O
,	O
she	O
warned	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
"	O
mounting	O
pressure	O
from	O
the	O
people	O
who	O
want	O
to	O
be	O
back	O
to	O
business	O
[	O
and	O
]	O
...	O
the	O
sympathy	O
is	O
waning	O
a	O
little	O
bit	O
,	O
especially	O
among	O
the	O
people	O
.	O


"	O
But	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
no	O
one	O
wants	O
to	O
give	O
up	O
.	O
They	O
know	O
they	O
have	O
done	O
something	O
unprecedented	O
in	O
this	O
area	O
,	O
in	O
this	O
region	O
,	O
especially	O
in	O
Egypt	COUNTRY
where	O
you	O
have	O
been	O
under	O
a	O
dictatorship	O
for	O
maybe	O
7,000	O
years	O
now	O
,"	O
said	O
Radi	PERSON
,	O
who	O
works	O
for	O
the	O
newswire	O
Agence	NEWSPAPER
France	NEWSPAPER
Presse	NEWSPAPER
and	O
the	O
newspaper	O
Al-Shorouk	NEWSPAPER
.	O


She	O
explained	O
that	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
main	O
impediments	O
for	O
protestors	O
to	O
succeed	O
is	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
not	O
unified	O
.	O
"	O
They	O
don	O
't	O
have	O
one	O
main	O
leader	O
to	O
talk	O
to	O
.	O
They	O
don	O
't	O
have	O
one	O
head	O
,	O
they	O
have	O
several	O
heads	O
,"	O
she	O
said	O
.	O
"	O
And	O
I	O
think	O
they	O
have	O
to	O
unify	O
their	O
voice	O
."	O


The	O
BBC	ORGANIZATION
's	O
John	PERSON
Simpson	PERSON
picked	O
up	O
on	O
the	O
idea	O
that	O
economic	O
trends	O
loom	O
large	O
in	O
determining	O
how	O
this	O
crisis	O
will	O
end	O
.	O
"	O
The	O
estimate	O
is	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
costing	O
this	O
country	O
$	O
300	O
million	O
every	O
single	O
day	O
.	O
I	O
just	O
think	O
it	O
's	O
not	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
possible	O
to	O
keep	O
the	O
pressure	O
up	O
sufficient	O
to	O
force	O
Mr	O
.	O
Mubarak	POLITICIAN
to	O
do	O
what	O
the	O
crowds	O
want	O
him	O
to	O
do	O
--	O
what	O
many	O
people	O
in	O
this	O
country	O
want	O
him	O
to	O
do	O
,"	O
Simpson	PERSON
said	O
.	O
Mubarak	POLITICIAN
has	O
"	O
played	O
that	O
stubbornness	O
card	O
,	O
which	O
often	O
seems	O
to	O
work	O
in	O
these	O
revolutionary	O
situations	O
.	O
He	O
's	O
not	O
moving	O
.	O
He	O
's	O
an	O
old	O
man	O
.	O
He	O
's	O
got	O
the	O
pride	O
and	O
the	O
stubbornness	O
of	O
an	O
old	O
man	O
."	O



=-DOCSTART-	O

 	O


Mamoudzou	CITY
is	O
the	O
capital	O
of	O
the	O
French	O
overseas	O
collectivity	O
of	O
Mayotte	COUNTRY
,	O
in	O
the	O
Indian	LOCATION
Ocean	LOCATION
.	O
Mamoudzou	CITY
is	O
the	O
most	O
populated	O
commune	O
(	O
municipality	O
)	O
of	O
Mayotte	COUNTRY
.	O
It	O
is	O
located	O
on	O
Grande-Terre	LOCATION
(	O
or	O
Mahoré	LOCATION
),	O
the	O
main	O
island	O
of	O
Mayotte	COUNTRY
.	O
The	O
former	O
capital	O
of	O
Mayotte	COUNTRY
was	O
Dzaoudzi	CITY
,	O
on	O
the	O
small	O
island	O
of	O
Petite-Terre	LOCATION
(	O
or	O
Pamanzi	LOCATION
),	O
but	O
Mamoudzou	CITY
was	O
chosen	O
as	O
the	O
capital	O
in	O
1977	O
.	O


Administration	O


The	O
commune	O
is	O
composed	O
of	O
6	O
villages	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
its	O
central	O
habitation	O
,	O
also	O
called	O
Mamoudzou	CITY
.	O
These	O
are	O
:	O
Kawéni	CITY
,	O
Mtsapéré	CITY
,	O
Passamainti	CITY
,	O
Vahibé	CITY
,	O
Tsoundzou	CITY
I	CITY
and	O
Tsoundzou	CITY
II	CITY
.	O


The	O
commune	O
is	O
also	O
subdivided	O
into	O
3	O
cantons	O
;	O
Mamoudzou	LOCATION
I	LOCATION
,	O
Mamoudzou	LOCATION
II	LOCATION
and	O
Mamoudzou	LOCATION
III	LOCATION
.	O


Demographics	O


=-DOCSTART-	O


Premier	O
gateway	O
to	O
the	O
many	O
islands	O
and	O
tourist	O
destinations	O
north	O
and	O
south	O
of	O
the	O
Philippines	COUNTRY
,	O
Metro	CITY
Manila	CITY
has	O
its	O
own	O
share	O
of	O
attractions	O
to	O
suit	O
every	O
interest	O
.	O
Here	O
,	O
churches	O
,	O
museums	O
and	O
theatres	O
vie	O
for	O
the	O
attentions	O
of	O
history	O
and	O
culture	O
buffs	O
.	O
Malls	O
,	O
boutiques	O
,	O
flea	O
markets	O
and	O
antique	O
shops	O
offer	O
endless	O
surprises	O
for	O
shoppers	O
and	O
souvenir-hunters	O
.	O
Posh	O
restaurants	O
and	O
sidewalk	O
eateries	O
entice	O
gastronomic	O
adventurers	O
.	O
Snazzy	O
discos	O
and	O
cozy	O
bars	O
entertain	O
the	O
night	O
owl	O
.	O
Golfing	O
greens	O
,	O
country	O
clubs	O
and	O
accessible	O
out-of-town	O
resorts	O
provide	O
recreation	O
and	O
relaxation	O
for	O
all	O
.	O
And	O
everywhere	O
,	O
a	O
friendly	O
,	O
festive	O
people	O
who	O
smile	O
readily	O
,	O
adore	O
music	O
and	O
love	O
to	O
welcome	O
visitors	O
with	O
their	O
world-famous	O
brand	O
of	O
hospitality	O
.	O

representative	O
,	O
banks	O
,	O
postal	O
services	O
,	O
car	O
rental	O
and	O
chartered	O
flight	O
services	O
,	O
a	O
medical	O
clinic	O
and	O
a	O
baggage	O
deposit	O
area	O
.	O
Philippine	ORGANIZATION
Airlines	ORGANIZATION
,	O
the	O
official	O
flag	O
carrier	O
,	O
links	O
Manila	CITY
to	O
26	O
cities	O
in	O
19	O
countries	O
and	O
provides	O
daily	O
service	O
to	O
and	O
from	O
42	O
major	O
destinations	O
within	O
the	O
country	O
.	O


Manila	CITY
's	O
passenger	O
and	O
container	O
ports	O
bustle	O
with	O
the	O
activities	O
of	O
several	O
local	O
and	O
international	O
shipping	O
concerns	O
.	O
Cruise	O
ships	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
chartered	O
and	O
private	O
vessels	O
,	O
find	O
berth	O
in	O
the	O
calm	O
waters	O
of	O
Manila	LOCATION
Bay	LOCATION
.	O

(	O
EDSA	MISC
)	O
the	O
major	O
artery	O
which	O
cuts	O
through	O
the	O
metropolis	O
and	O
connects	O
important	O
Train	O
plies	O
the	O
rail	O
route	O
from	O
Tutuban	LOCATION
in	O
Manila	CITY
to	O
as	O
far	O
southward	O
as	O
Cavite	LOCATION
Province	LOCATION
;	O
while	O
the	O
Metro	MISC
Ferry	MISC
cross	O
the	O
Pasig	LOCATION
River	LOCATION
from	O
Fscolta	LOCATION
,	O
Manila	CITY
to	O
Guadalupe	LOCATION
,	O
Makati	CITY
.	O
Taxis	O
about	O
along	O
major	O
streets	O
and	O
within	O
commercial	O
and	O
business	O
centers	O
.	O
Tricycles	O
(	O
motorcycles	O
with	O
side	O
cars	O
)	O
and	O
pedicabs	O
(	O
bicycles	O
with	O
side	O
cars	O
)	O
service	O
narrow	O
roads	O
and	O
inner	O
city	O
alleys	O
.	O
In	O
sections	O
of	O
Manila	CITY
like	O
Binondo	LOCATION
in	O
Chinatown	LOCATION
and	O
Intramuros	LOCATION
,	O
Kalesas	LOCATION
or	O
horse-drawn	O

It	O
is	O
almost	O
impossible	O
to	O
run	O
out	O
of	O
things	O
to	O
see	O
and	O
do	O
in	O
Metro	O
Manila	CITY
.	O
Magnificent	O
churches	O
of	O
impressive	O
architectural	O
proportions	O
with	O
their	O
interiors	O
chock-full	O
of	O
relics	O
testify	O
to	O
the	O
centuries-old	O
religious	O
tradition	O
of	O
the	O
Filipinos	O
.	O
Parks	O
and	O
shaded	O
plazas	O
deliver	O
rest	O
to	O
weary	O
feet	O
;	O
markers	O
and	O
monuments	O
provide	O
insights	O
into	O
significant	O
events	O
and	O
people	O
in	O
local	O
history	O
.	O
Museums	O
and	O
art	O
galleries	O
acquaint	O
visitors	O
with	O
the	O
country	O
's	O
rich	O
cultural	O
,	O
historical	O
and	O
artistic	O
heritage	O
.	O


The	O
visitor	O
may	O
also	O
want	O
to	O
spend	O
time	O
watching	O
a	O
movie	O
,	O
as	O
a	O
great	O
number	O
of	O
Filipinos	O
do	O
.	O
There	O
are	O
more	O
than	O
246	O
movie	O
houses	O
in	O
Metro	O
Manila	CITY
alone	O
,	O
making	O
the	O
Philippines	COUNTRY
the	O
film	O
capital	O
of	O
Asia	LOCATION
.	O
Majority	O
of	O
these	O
movie	O
houses	O
show	O
American	O
films	O
.	O


In	O
Manila	CITY
,	O
visit	O
Malacanang	LOCATION
Palace	LOCATION
,	O
official	O
residence	O
of	O
the	O
Philippine	O
heads	O
of	O
state	O
;	O
stroll	O
through	O
Rizal	LOCATION
Park	LOCATION
,	O
Paco	LOCATION
Park	LOCATION
or	O
Intramuros	LOCATION
the	O
old	O
walled	O
city	O
or	O
head	O
for	O
Quiapo	LOCATION
and	O
Chinatown	LOCATION
for	O
a	O
dash	O
of	O
local	O
color	O
.	O
For	O
more	O
outdoor	O
fun	O
and	O
entertainment	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
sunset	O
cruises	O
around	O
Manila	LOCATION
Bay	LOCATION
and	O
open-air	O
cultural	O
events	O
held	O
Friday	O
evenings	O
at	O
Paco	LOCATION
Park	LOCATION
,	O
Saturday	O
evenings	O
at	O
Puerta	LOCATION
Real	LOCATION
in	O
Intramuros	LOCATION
and	O
Sunday	O
afternoons	O
at	O
Rizal	LOCATION
Park	LOCATION
.	O
Explore	O
the	O
museums	O
of	O
the	O
Cultural	LOCATION
Center	LOCATION
of	LOCATION
the	LOCATION
Philippines	LOCATION
located	O
along	O
Roxas	LOCATION
Boulevard	LOCATION
.	O


In	O
Makati	CITY
,	O
spend	O
time	O
at	O
the	O
Ayala	LOCATION
Museum	LOCATION
for	O
a	O
look	O
at	O
the	O
historical	O
dioramas	O
depicting	O
significant	O
events	O
in	O
Philippine	O
history	O
.	O
The	O
museum	O
also	O
has	O
excellent	O
models	O
of	O
Southeast	LOCATION
Asian	LOCATION
watercraft	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
archaeological	O
artifacts	O
.	O


Farther	O
north	O
in	O
Quezon	CITY
City	CITY
are	O
the	O
Quezon	LOCATION
Memorial	LOCATION
Circle	LOCATION
and	O
the	O
Ninoy	LOCATION
Aquino	LOCATION
Parks	LOCATION
and	LOCATION
Wildlife	LOCATION
Center	LOCATION
.	O
On	O
these	O
tree-shaded	O
open	O
spaces	O
,	O
get	O
a	O
whiff	O
of	O
fresh	O
air	O
,	O
go	O
biking	O
or	O
roller-skating	O
,	O
or	O
just	O
soak	O
in	O
the	O
peace	O
and	O
quiet	O
.	O


Sports	O
:	O


Metro	O
Manila	CITY
's	O
11	O
golfing	O
greens	O
are	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
best	O
places	O
to	O
tee	O
off	O
in	O
Asia	LOCATION
.	O
Aside	O
from	O
inexpensive	O
fees	O
and	O
club	O
amenities	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
the	O
bonuses	O
of	O
fresh-air	O
,	O
balmy	O
sunshine	O
and	O
friendly	O
,	O
English-speaking	O
caddies	O
who	O
offer	O
solicited	O
advice	O
.	O
Rates	O
vary	O
from	O
course	O
to	O
course	O
.	O
For	O
spectator	O
sports	O
with	O
a	O
dash	O
of	O
local	O
color	O
,	O
nothing	O
beats	O
the	O
horse-races	O
at	O
the	O
Sta	LOCATION
.	LOCATION
Ana	LOCATION
Tracks	LOCATION
and	O
at	O
the	O
San	LOCATION
Lazaro	LOCATION
Hippodrome	LOCATION
.	O

Head	O
for	O
Ongpin	LOCATION
Street	LOCATION
in	O
Chinatown	LOCATION
!	O
where	O
Chinese	O
Filipinos	O
go	O
for	O
a	O
taste	O
of	O
true	O
mainland	O
delicacies	O
.	O
Eat	O
your	O
way	O
through	O
the	O
restaurant	O
rows	O
of	O
Malate	LOCATION
and	O
Roxas	LOCATION
Boulevard	LOCATION
as	O
you	O
savor	O
the	O
sea	O
breezes	O
and	O
watch	O
a	O
spectacular	O
sunset	O
.	O
Farther	O
down	O
Roxas	LOCATION
Boulevard	LOCATION
towards	O
the	O
Cavite	O
coastline	O
,	O
take	O
your	O
pick	O
of	O
fresh	O
seafood	O
cooked	O
to	O
your	O
specifications	O
in	O
the	O
many	O
restaurants	O
lining	O
the	O
road	O
.	O


A	O
peek	O
into	O
the	O
basements	O
of	O
Metro	O
Manila	CITY
's	O
shopping	O
malls	O
will	O
reveal	O
steaming	O
fastfood	O
counters	O
serving	O
everything	O
from	O
pasta	O
,	O
salads	O
and	O
sizzling	O
steaks	O
to	O
kimchi	O
,	O
sushi	O
and	O
lechon	O
As	O
the	O
sun	O
goes	O
down	O
,	O
the	O
lights	O
go	O
up	O
in	O
Metro	CITY
Manila	CITY
's	O
nightspots	O
.	O
First-class	O
hotels	O
and	O
restaurants	O
attract	O
diners	O
with	O
performances	O
by	O
local	O
pop	O
artists	O
,	O
folk	O
dance	O
troupes	O
,	O
string	O
quartets	O
and	O
jazz	O
bands	O
.	O
Theater	O
and	O
repertory	O
acts	O
,	O
classical	O
concerts	O
and	O
ballet	O
performances	O
cater	O
to	O
the	O
well	O
dressed	O
set	O
who	O
frequent	O
the	O
Cultural	LOCATION
Center	LOCATION
of	LOCATION
the	LOCATION
Philippines	LOCATION
,	O
the	O
Manila	LOCATION
Metropolitan	LOCATION
Theater	LOCATION
,	O
the	O
Repertory	LOCATION
Theater	LOCATION
at	O
Shangri-La	LOCATION
Plaza	LOCATION
and	O
other	O
theaters	O
throughout	O
the	O
city	O
.	O


For	O
endless	O
evenings	O
of	O
dancing	O
,	O
music	O
and	O
people-watching	O
,	O
head	O
for	O
the	O
bright	O
lights	O
along	O
Makati	LOCATION
Avenue	LOCATION
and	O
Pasay	LOCATION
Road	LOCATION
in	O
Makati	CITY
,	O
along	O
Quezon	LOCATION
Boulevard	LOCATION
,	O
Timog	O
and	O
West	LOCATION
Avenues	LOCATION
in	O
Quezon	CITY
City	CITY
,	O
Greenhills	LOCATION
in	O
San	CITY
Juan	CITY
,	O
and	O
Roxas	LOCATION
Boulevard	LOCATION
and	O
Malate	LOCATION
in	O
Manila	CITY
.	O
Trendy	O
discos	O
with	O
their	O
flashing	O
lights	O
and	O
pulsating	O

There	O
are	O
two	O
casinos	O
for	O
those	O
who	O
wish	O
to	O
try	O
their	O
luck	O
at	O
cards	O
,	O
roulette	O
or	O
the	O
slot	O
machines	O
.	O
Along	O
the	O
sunset	O
strip	O
of	O
Ermita	LOCATION
,	O
chug	O
a	O
mug	O
of	O
chilled	O
local	O
beer	O
with	O
platters	O
of	O
pulutan	O
(	O
finger	O
foods	O
)	O
and	O
a	O
liberal	O
dash	O
of	O
pulchritude	O
.	O


Shopping	O
:	O


It	O
is	O
extremely	O
easy	O
for	O
the	O
happy	O
shopper	O
to	O
get	O
lost	O
in	O
Metro	CITY
Manila	CITY
's	O
treasure	O
trove	O
of	O
malls	O
,	O
flea	O
markets	O
,	O
bargain	O
centers	O
and	O
antique	O
shops	O
.	O
On	O
your	O
way	O
to	O
the	O
city	O
from	O
the	O
airport	O
,	O
stop	O
at	O
the	O
handicrafts	O
shops	O
strategically	O
located	O
along	O
the	O
road	O
.	O

appliance	O
centers	O
,	O
shops	O
and	O
furniture	O
,	O
optical	O
and	O
jewelry	O
shops	O
,	O
and	O
drugstores	O
,	O
gourmet	O
restaurants	O
and	O
fastfood	O
galleries	O
.	O
Flock	O
to	O
these	O
malls	O
malls	O
any	O
day	O
of	O
the	O
week	O
for	O
dining	O
and	O
movie-watching	O
.	O


Flea	O
market	O
stalls	O
crowd	O
the	O
congested	O
streets	O
of	O
Quiapo	CITY
Divisoria	CITY
and	O
Baclaran	CITY
where	O
bargain-hunters	O
jostle	O
and	O
haggle	O
for	O
the	O
best	O
buy	O
in	O
fabric	O
,	O
ready-to-wear	O
clothing	O
,	O
shoes	O
and	O
slippers	O
,	O
houseware	O
and	O
home	O
decor	O
items	O
and	O
fresh	O
produce	O
.	O
Loves	O
of	O
and	O
handicrafts	O
rummage	O
around	O
antique	O
shops	O
on	O
streets	O
of	O
Malate	LOCATION
Manila	CITY
and	O
San	CITY
Juan	CITY
for	O
relics	O
,	O
old	O
santos	O
(	O
images	O
of	O
saints	O
),	O
altarpieces	O
,	O
vases	O
,	O
ceramics	O
,	O
baskets	O
,	O
earthenware	O
and	O
brassware	O
.	O


Convention	O
Facilities	O
:	O


Metro	CITY
Manila	CITY
is	O
well-equip	O
modern	O
facilities	O
and	O
services	O
for	O
international	O
convent	O
Philippine	LOCATION
International	LOCATION
Convention	LOCATION
Center	LOCATION
Complex	LOCATION
on	O
Roxas	LOCATION
Boulevard	LOCATION
is	O
the	O
premier	O
convention	O
center	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
.	O
It	O
has	O
a	O
large	O
convention	O
hall	O
which	O
can	O
accommodate	O
up	O
to	O
4,000	O
people	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
meeting	O
groups	O
of	O
100	O
to	O
1,000	O
.	O
Most	O
deluxe	O
hotels	O
within	O
the	O
facilities	O
for	O
smaller	O
groups	O
.	O
Out-of-town	O
resort	O
hotel	O
are	O
alternative	O
convention	O
sites	O
.	O
The	O
Philippine	ORGANIZATION
Convention	ORGANIZATION
Visitors	ORGANIZATION
Corporation	ORGANIZATION
(	O
PCVC	ORGANIZATION
)	O
has	O
a	O
Conventions	O
and	O
Travel	O
Unit	O
which	O
provides	O
comprehensive	O
information	O
,	O
technical	O
assistance	O
and	O
guidance	O
to	O
convention	O
planners	O
and	O
incentive	O
tide	O
travel	O
organizers	O
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


Home	O

The	O
aircraft	O
was	O
shot	O
down	O
by	O
Abkhazian	O
rebels	O
after	O
a	O
flight	O
from	O
Tbilisi	CITY
.	O
The	O
Tu-154	AIRPLANE
crashed	O
onto	O
the	O
runway	O
and	O
caught	O
fire	O
.	O

This	O
map	O
shows	O
the	O
airport	O
of	O
departure	O
and	O
the	O
intended	O
destination	O
of	O
the	O
flight	O
.	O
The	O
line	O
between	O
the	O
airports	O
does	O
not	O
display	O
the	O
exact	O
flight	O
path	O
.	O

Distance	O
from	O
Tbilisi-Novo	AIRPORT
Alexeyevka	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
(	O
TBS	AIRPORT
)	O
(	O
TBS	AIRPORT
/	AIRPORT
UGGG	AIRPORT
)	O
to	O
Sukhumi-Babusheri	AIRPORT
Airport	AIRPORT
(	O
SUI	AIRPORT
)	O
(	O
SUI	AIRPORT
/	AIRPORT
UGSS	AIRPORT
)	O
as	O
the	O
crow	O
flies	O
is	O
340	O
km	O
(	O
213	O
miles	O
).	O


This	O
information	O
is	O
not	O
presented	O
as	O
the	O
Flight	ORGANIZATION
Safety	ORGANIZATION
Foundation	ORGANIZATION
or	O
the	O
Aviation	ORGANIZATION
Safety	ORGANIZATION
Network	ORGANIZATION
's	O
opinion	O
as	O
to	O
the	O
cause	O
of	O
the	O
accident	O
.	O
It	O
is	O
preliminary	O
and	O
is	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
facts	O
as	O
they	O
are	O
known	O
at	O
this	O
time	O
.	O


Cite	O
this	O
page	O
:	O


Criminal	O
Occurrence	O
description	O
.	O
The	O
Aviation	ORGANIZATION
Safety	ORGANIZATION
Network	ORGANIZATION
Website	ORGANIZATION
.	O
Last	O
updated	O
:	O
12	O
February	O
2011	O
.	O


=-DOCSTART-	O


January	O
29	O
,	O
2010	O
(	O
CHICAGO	CITY
)	O
(	O
WLS	MISC
)	O
--	O

A	O
Polish	O
politician	O
who	O
spearheaded	O
the	O
movement	O
that	O
led	O
to	O
the	O
fall	O
of	O
communism	O
in	O
Poland	COUNTRY
is	O
taking	O
a	O
stand	O
in	O
Illinois	LOCATION
politics	O
.	O


Lech	POLITICIAN
Walesa	POLITICIAN
,	O
the	O
former	O
polish	O
president	O
,	O
is	O
endorsing	O
Polish-American	O
Adam	POLITICIAN
Andrzejewski	POLITICIAN
in	O
the	O
Republican	O
race	O
for	O
governor	O
.	O


Walesa	POLITICIAN
an	O
iconic	O
figure	O
of	O
Poland	COUNTRY
's	O
rise	O
from	O
communism	O
but	O
today	O
Lech	POLITICIAN
Walesa	POLITICIAN
is	O
hoping	O
to	O
give	O
Adam	POLITICIAN
Andrzejewski	POLITICIAN
a	O
lift	O
in	O
the	O
race	O
for	O
governor	O
.	O
he	O
two	O
men	O
joined	O
together	O
for	O
an	O
event	O
at	O
the	O
Union	ORGANIZATION
League	ORGANIZATION
Club	ORGANIZATION
of	ORGANIZATION
Chicago	ORGANIZATION
.	O

Walesa	POLITICIAN
says	O
his	O
endorsement	O
is	O
about	O
more	O
than	O
merely	O
sharing	O
Polish	O
heritage	O
.	O
He	O
believes	O
the	O
Hinsdale	MISC
businessman	O
would	O
bring	O
a	O
new	O
honest	O
approach	O
to	O
Illinois	LOCATION
government	O
.	O


"	O
Because	O
he	O
has	O
no	O
baggage	O
.	O
He	O
is	O
open	O
.	O
He	O
can	O
put	O
things	O
in	O
order	O
.	O
Clean	O
house	O
,"	O
said	O
Walesa	POLITICIAN
.	O


The	O
former	O
Polish	O
president	O
is	O
well	O
aware	O
of	O
the	O
stain	O
of	O
corruption	O
in	O
Illinois	LOCATION
politics	O
.	O
He	O
joked	O
,	O
tongue-in-cheek	O
,	O
that	O
he	O
won	O
't	O
need	O
to	O
visit	O
his	O
chosen	O
candidate	O
in	O
prison	O
.	O


"	O
He	O
doesn	O
't	O
depend	O
on	O
anyone	O
and	O
this	O
is	O
his	O
greatness	O
,"	O
said	O
Walesa	POLITICIAN
.	O


"	O
We	O
're	O
gonna	O
defend	O
the	O
taxpayers	O
of	O
Illinois	LOCATION
.	O
We	O
're	O
gonna	O
bring	O
good	O
governance	O
to	O
Springfield	CITY
.	O
This	O
is	O
a	O
new	O
era	O
of	O
governance	O
that	O
we	O
can	O
work	O
on	O
together	O
,"	O
said	O
Andrzejewski	POLITICIAN
.	O


But	O
Andrzejewski	POLITICIAN
has	O
his	O
work	O
cut	O
out	O
for	O
him	O
.	O


It	O
's	O
a	O
tough	O
six-way	O
race	O
containing	O
more	O
familiar	O
names	O
in	O
Illinois	LOCATION
politics	O
for	O
the	O
Republican	O
nomination	O
.	O


Andrzejewski	POLITICIAN
doesn	O
't	O
seem	O
to	O
mind	O
the	O
underdog	O
status	O
and	O
neither	O
does	O
Lech	POLITICIAN
Walesa	POLITICIAN
.	O


"	O
Nobody	O
gave	O
us	O
a	O
chance	O
to	O
win	O
over	O
the	O
communists	O
.	O
Nobody	O
.	O
And	O
we	O
proved	O
them	O
wrong	O
,"	O
said	O
Walesa	POLITICIAN
.	O



=-DOCSTART-	O


From	O
Academic	O
Kids	O

Indira	POLITICIAN
Priyadarshini	POLITICIAN
Gandhi	POLITICIAN
(	O
November	O
19	O
,	O
1917	O
–	O
October	O
31	O
,	O
1984	O
)	O
was	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
of	O
India	COUNTRY
from	O
January	O
19	O
,	O
1966	O
to	O
March	O
24	O
,	O
1977	O
,	O
and	O
from	O
January	O
14	O
,	O
1980	O
until	O
her	O
assassination	O
in	O
1984	O
.	O

A	O
brilliant	O
political	O
strategist	O
and	O
thinker	O
,	O
Indira	POLITICIAN
also	O
possessed	O
an	O
extraordinary	O
desire	O
for	O
political	O
power	O
.	O
As	O
a	O
woman	O
occupying	O
the	O
highest	O
position	O
of	O
government	O
in	O
,	O
what	O
was	O
at	O
that	O
time	O
,	O
a	O
very	O
patriarchal	O
society	O
,	O
Indira	POLITICIAN
was	O
expected	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
passive	O
leader	O
,	O
but	O
her	O
actions	O
proved	O
her	O
otherwise	O
.	O

